双语合并：Hodoscope
《迷失之城》
你太棒了
You were incredible.
我的心跳还是好快
My heart is still racing.
我也感觉到了
I felt it too.
这全要归功于你强健的体魄 达什
All thanks to your brute strength, Dash,
还有你对古阿拉姆数学知识的了解
and your knowledge of ancient Aramaic mathematics.
行了 这和我的两个博士学位
Please. This has nothing to do with my two doctorates
以及性别研究硕士学位都毫无关系
and my master's in Gender Studies
这都得归功于你 洛芙摩尔博士
and everything to do with you, Dr. Lovemore.
实际上
The truth is,
我从没想到我会找到迷失之城D
I never thought I would find the Lost City of D.
你们俩最好说话小心点
I would choose your words carefully.
这会是你们的遗言
They will be your last.
你们把我带到卡拉曼国王的陵墓
You led me right to King Kalaman's tomb
找到了传说中王后的火焰皇冠
and his queen's legendary Crown of Fire.
现在我会变成大富翁
And now I will be very rich,
而你们则会死翘翘
and you will be very dead.
等等 这些蛇是你的吗？
Hold up. Are these your snakes?
不是 本来就有的
No, they were just here.
这寺庙里有几百条蛇
There were just hundreds of snakes in this temple
就在这里等着我们来？
just waiting for us to show up?
-谁喂它们？你吗？ -不 它们吃什么？
-Who feeds them? You feed them? -No, what do they eat?
那条蛇为什么不咬那个人？ 这是怎么回事？
Why is that one not biting that guy? Why is that happening?
它们受过训练不咬坏人手下还是怎的？
Are they trained not to bite henchmen or something?
这…
Yeah, well…
光是一座庙里这么多蛇就已经…
I mean, the snake-to-temple ratio alone…
太荒谬了 删除
This is ridiculous. Delete.
我觉得我的角色还是说得过去的
I think my character can still work.
删除
Delete.
洛蕾塔 你还有个故事要写呢
Loretta, you still have a story to write.
删除
Delete.
喂 是我 贝丝
Hey, it's me, Beth.
我也不想拿出版商的头衔压你 但我没办法
I don't want to pull the whole "I'm your publisher" card, but I am.
我真的非常期待看到这最后一章
And I'm really looking forward to seeing this last chapter.
不过 别有压力 不 其实是有压力的
But no pressure. No, there actually is pressure.
压力的大小恰好能激励你
The exact amount of pressure that motivates you
但不至于压垮你
but doesn't paralyze you.
你可以的
You got this.
（晚饭）
谢谢
Thank you.
还是我
Me again.
好 签书会已经万事俱备
Okay, so everything is set for the book tour,
但唯独就差了那本书
but the only thing we need is a book to tour with.
我不禁觉得你之所以没有写完
I can't help but get the feeling that you're not finishing
是因为你想继续赖在家里不出门
because you don't want to leave your house.
听着 我知道约翰 去世后的这五年
Listen, I know these last five years have been hard
你过得不容易
after John's passing,
你觉得整天赖在浴缸里
and it feels easier to live in your bathtub,
喝加冰白葡萄酒会好受些
drinking Chardonnay on ice.
但是 姑娘 大千世界正等着你
But, girl, there is a great big world waiting for you
而且签书会也没法取消
and a book tour that I can't cancel,
所以你配合一下 行不？
so just make it happen, all right?
爱你哦 拜
Love you, bye!
我们得继续前进
We have to keep going.
去看看那扇门的另一边有什么
Let's see what's on the other side of that door.
万一什么都没有呢？
But what if there isn't anything?
想知道只有一个办法
There's only one way to find out.
然后洛芙摩尔意识到
Then Lovemore realized
她想要的宝藏已经再也找不到了
the treasure she wanted was lost forever
她的冒险之旅走到了尽头
and her adventures were coming to an end.
这感觉不太对
That doesn't feel right.
是的 但就这样了
Yeah, but that's it.
结束了
That's the end.
约翰
Well, John,
我完成了
here I go.
苦后更甜
Dulcius ex asperis.
（洛蕾塔塞琪 《迷失之城D》）
好了 亲爱的 该上台了
Okay, honey, it's showtime.
你确定这样可以吗？
Are you sure about this?
这裤裆前后都勒得慌
Because I have a wedgie in the back and in the front in this thing.
我感觉自己就像个滑花样滑冰的傻大姐
I feel like a nerdy figure skater.
-性感尤物 我爱极了 -不 不是的
-Sexy. Stunner. I'm all about it. -No, it's not. It's not.
-穿这个我怎么动？ -别摸了
-How do I move in this? -Don't touch it.
-我没摸 我在拽裤裆 -行了 你有完没完？
-I'm not touching it. I'm holding it out. -Stop it. Will you stop?
现在就拽出来 上台了可不能这样
Get it out now 'cause you can't do that onstage.
行了 可以了 好的
And we're done. And we're done. Okay, good.
真有穿亮片连身衣的必要吗？
Do I need to be wearing a glitter onesie?
只要穿两个小时就行
You only have to wear this for two hours.
别弄坏了 听到没？这是租来的
Do not mess this up, do you hear me? This is on loan.
现在就流行穿亮片
Everyone's wearing sequins right now.
-她为什么在拍我？ -她是艾莉森
-Why is she taking my photo? -This is Allison.
我们的新社交媒体经理
She is our new social media manager.
她会帮我们瞄准更年轻的读者群
And she's gonna be helping us target that younger demographic.
也就是那些30多岁
Meaning women in their 30s
希望自己还是20多岁的女性
who wish they were in their 20s.
嗨 你好啊
Hey, what's up?
我接管了你的社交媒体
I took over your socials,
今早你在推特上发帖说
so this morning you tweeted,
“我的姐妹们在哪里？
"Where are my ladies at?
下午5点 我在舞厅G等你们
Meet me at Ballroom G at 5:00 p.m.
主题标签 肖恩门德斯
#ShawnMendes.
主题标签 等不及见到大家”
#GaggingToMeetYouAll."
好 我们会很开心的 走吧
Okay, we are having fun. Let's go.
我们得提醒大家你还活着
We need to remind people that you are still alive.
他们知道我还活着
People know I'm alive.
还要提醒他们 这为什么曾是最畅销的系列
And to remind them why this used to be the best selling franchise.
言情小说
In Romance.
对 也是最来钱的文学类别
Yes, which is the top revenue-generating literary category.
预售成绩谈不上来钱
Revenue-generating isn't how I would describe our presales right now.
就把这当成是口碑营销好了
Just think of this as a way that uses word of mouth.
你要口碑是吗？好 这个怎么样？
You want word of mouth? Here we go. How's this?
“唯一比迷失之城更迷失的 就是作者本人”
"The only thing more lost than the city is the author herself."
“没有爱情” “没有激情”
"Loveless." "Passionless."
“她的巅峰早就过去了” 还有
"Way past her prime." And,
“这是最差劲的伪历史架空文”
"This is fake history at its worst."
开签书会就能扭转乾坤 好吗？
A book tour could change everything, okay?
我们得让粉丝们想起来
We have to remind the fans
他们为什么那么喜欢你
why they love you so much.
是真实历史 我只不过 加了一点点
Real history. I merely season it
裸体内容来增添情趣而已
with a smidge more nudity.
历史上的裸体内容多了去了
History had a ton of nudity.
深深的探索
Deep exploration.
火热的追求
Steamy wondering.
洛芙摩尔和达什是否能找到
Will Lovemore and Dash find
塔哈王后的无价之宝 火焰皇冠？
Queen Taha's priceless Crown of Fire?
与他们一起踏上探索之旅
Join them on their search.
是这样的 我有件事要跟你说
So, listen, I wanted to talk to you about something.
好多人
There's so many people.
我知道你讨厌这档事
I know how much you hate doing these things,
所以我邀请了艾伦 今天来和你一起做问答环节
so I've invited Alan to do the Q and A with you today.
-什么？ -还有剩下的签书会活动
-What? -And the rest of the book tour.
贝丝 我明确要求过
Beth, I expressly asked
不再和达什…艾伦一起参加活动
not to do any more events with Dash-- Alan, Alan!
-他会让我丢脸的 -他不会让你丢脸的
-He's gonna humiliate me. -He's not gonna humiliate you.
谢谢 你的工作非常出色 十分感谢
Thank you. You're very good at your job. Thank you so much. Thank you.
我来帮你吧
Let me help you with that.
他就是个沐浴露招牌
He's a body wash commercial.
总是浑身油亮亮的
He's always glistening all over the place.
没有哪次活动他不脱衬衫
There hasn't been an event where his shirt didn't come flying off.
-你想得美 -他已经来了
-You wish. -Well, he's already here,
所以拿出点大姑娘的样子 上台去吧
so put on your big-girl panties and let's get out there.
记住 不许板着脸
Remember, no grumpy face,
不许用艰深词汇 不许谈无聊的学术内容
big words or boring academic talk.
好极了 我们来啦 浪漫书页会
Yes! Yes! Come on, RTP!
洛芙摩尔的粉丝们
Yes, my Lovemore-heads!
我非常荣幸地向大家介绍
I am so excited to introduce to you
获奖作家 洛蕾塔塞琪！
the award-winning author, Loretta Sage!
贝丝 我不行 我还没准备好
Beth, I can't do this. I'm not ready.
你开什么玩笑？
Are you kidding me?
听着 有我在别怕
Listen, I've got your back.
你可以的 去满足读者们的愿望
You got this. Go give the people what they want.
-他们的愿望不是我 -快点上去
-It's not me they want. -Get out there now!
嗨 大家好 很高兴见到你们 谢谢
Hi. How are you? Nice to see you. Thank you.
对 爬上去
Yep. Mount it.
爬上去 好
Mount it. Mount it. Okay.
坐稳了
Find your center.
现在是大家期待已久的时刻
And now, the moment you've all been waiting for.
-最性感… -好！
-The sexiest… -All right!
…最具影响力的英雄人物 我们的时代之最
…most influential hero of a generation.
有点夸张了
That's a bit strong.
第20次登上安琪拉洛芙摩尔小说的封面
His 20th cover of an Angela Lovemore novel.
达什麦克马洪
Dash McMahon!
天啊 达什
Oh, my God! Dash!
-来鞠个躬 -我已经鞠过了 鞠过了
-Take a bow. -I already did mine. I did mine.
来吧 再鞠一个 有我在
Okay, come on. One more. I got you.
你们之前排练过吗？天啊
Did you guys rehearse that? Oh, my God.
我真喜欢你们之间来电的感觉
I'm loving this chemistry between you two, and I got to say,
我超喜欢这本书
I love this book.
-谢谢你 雷伊 -谢…
-Thank you, Ray. -Thank--
剧透警告
Spoiler alert.
结局没有让他们俩进入陵墓
A really bold choice to not have them
这个选择相当大胆
go into the tomb at the end.
请说说你是怎么想的
Talk about what went into this one.
对我个人而言 这本书非常特别
This one's such a special book for me personally.
对我意义重大 我简直不知道该怎么说
I don't know how to say how much it means to me
因为洛蕾塔 了不起的大作家
that Loretta, word writer extraordinaire,
以我的名字命名了这本书
has named the book after me.
《迷失之城达什》
The Lost City of Dash.
《迷失之城D》
The Lost City of D.
“D”其实不是这个意思
But that's not what the D stands for.
“D”是指“小弟弟” 对吧？
It's D for "dick," right?
不是“小弟弟” 不是
No dick, no.
是基于一个古老部落的名字
It's based on the name of an ancient tribe,
“达波卡吉欧迪斯弗米卡”
Dapocagihou-dysphem-ica.
欧洲殖民者觉得这个名字太拗口
It was too difficult for the European colonizers to pronounce,
-于是他们就用了缩写… -没人想听这些
-so, in true colonial fashion… -No one cares about this.
…典型的殖民主义风格
…they abbreviated it.
真有意思
That's so interesting.
好 不如我们来回答观众提问吧？
Okay. How about we take some questions from the audience?
-这边 帅哥 -就你吧
-Right here, handsome! -Yes.
达什 你最喜欢哪一个浪漫时刻？
Dash, what's your favorite romantic moment?
我真正想知道的是
What I would really like to know is
洛蕾塔最喜欢哪个浪漫时刻？
what is Loretta's favorite romantic moment?
好火辣哦
Ooh, spicy.
作为一个智性恋者…
Well, being a sapiosexual--
是指那种用蛇绕着…
Is that when they do the snakes around the…
不是 是指那些被才学
No. That's someone who finds intellect
或者智慧吸引的人
or intelligence very sexy, you know.
我也是
Same.
是吗？
Really?
达什 把衬衣扒了
Dash! Rip off your shirt!
不 今天就算了
No, no, no. We're not gonna do that today.
今天的主题是洛蕾塔的新书
We're here for Loretta's book.
大家有问题要问洛蕾塔吗？
Do we have questions for Loretta?
这位看上去很好学的年轻女士
Yes, studious-looking young lady?
你想问我什么问题？
What would you like to ask me?
你能扒了达什的衬衣吗？
Can you rip off Dash's shirt?
不 不能再来一次 抱歉
No, we're not gonna do this again. Sorry.
扒衣服！
Rip it off! Rip it off!
当然 没问题
Of course. Of course, yes. Can do.
真的要扒？
Is this happening?
-你不必这么做 -必须的
-You don't have to do this. -We have to.
必须满足读者们的愿望 没错
We have to give the people what they want. Yes, yes.
要满足大家的愿望 对
We have to give the people what they want, yes.
女士们 先生们 请好好享用
Ladies and gentlemen, enjoy.
因为《迷失之城D》 是达什的最后一次冒险
Because The Lost City of D is Dash's final adventure.
如果还有下一本书的话
If there even is a next book,
在故事一开头 洛芙摩尔就会收到
it will open with Lovemore receiving the tragic news
他英年早逝的噩耗
of his untimely death.
什么？
What?
-该死 对不起 手表勾住了 -等一下
-Shit. I'm sorry. My smartwatch is stuck. -Hold on.
我知道 不要拽
I know. Don't pull it.
没事 你别动就行
It's okay. Just be real still.
-不 你在拽 -是你在拽
-No. That's pulling it. -You're pulling it.
你会把我假发拽掉的 不 你不能…
You're gonna rip my wig off. No, you can't--
老天爷
Oh, my!
-天啊 -他没事吧？
-Oh, my God. -Is he okay?
天啊 对不起 真对不起
God, I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
真对不起
I'm so sorry.
你真恶毒
You're a bad person.
下午6点还有变装比赛 别走开哦
Stick around for the costume contest at 6:00 p.m.
什么叫“如果还有下一本书”？
"If there is another book"?
我把我们的全部身家
I'm investing everything we've got
都押在这趟签书会上了 好吗？
into this tour, okay?
我只是觉得我已经写不出
I just don't think I have another
达什和洛芙摩尔的冒险了
Dash and Lovemore adventure in me.
达什怎么死的？
How does Dash die?
-被蛇咬死的？ -不是
-Was it the snakes? -No.
好吧 我还有事情要处理
Okay, so I have something that I have to take care of.
你们俩10分钟后要去隔壁接受采访
You guys have an interview in the next suite in ten minutes.
劳驾你们帮个忙 拿出成年人的样子
So can you please do me a favor and be grown-ups
自己乖乖过去 好吧？
and get yourselves there on your own?
好 多谢
Okay. Thank you so much.
他是感染葡萄球菌死的吗？
Does he die from a staph infection?
就是葡萄球菌感染 果不其然
It is a staph infection. I knew it.
我…好吧
I-- All right.
如果你想歇一歇喘口气什么的 我理解
Look, I get it if you need a break or something,
-但你不能就这么把我写死 好吧？ -好吧
-but you can't just kill me, okay? -Okay.
我真不想这么说
I hate that I have to ask this,
但你不是达什 这你知道吧？
but you do know you're not Dash, right?
达什是我笔下虚构的人物
Dash is a character I made up.
达什？
Dash?
-谢谢 -谢谢你
-Thanks. -Thank you.
-洛蕾塔 这边 -不 我觉得是这边
-Loretta, it's this way. -No, I think it's this way.
你难道看不出达什对大家很重要吗？
Can't you see that Dash means so much to people?
-是对你很重要 -不是对我
-Means so much to you. -Not to me.
好吧 是对我 但对其他人也是
Well, yeah, to me, but to other people too.
-贝丝怎么办？ -贝丝不会有事的
-What about Beth? -You know what? Beth is gonna be fine.
她会找到很多才思泉涌的新生代年轻作家
She's gonna find plenty fresh, young writers full of great ideas.
你可以优雅转型
You can transition gracefully
进入你模特生涯的不脱衬衣阶段
into the shirt-on phase of your modeling career,
而我就能清静清静
and I can be left alone.
大家都开心
Everybody is happy.
不 应该是这边
No, it's this way.
贝丝说你现在连家门都不出
Beth says you don't even leave the house anymore.
我觉得这样并不是很开心
I don't feel like that's very happy.
你应该出去走走
You should be going out in the world,
接触新鲜的事物
filling yourself up on new experiences.
我已经接触够了 我已经完全满足了
I'm already filled up. I'm full. I'm fully satiated.
既然能出去见世面 为什么要
Why would you want to be stuck at home alone
一个人闷在家里呢？
when you could see the world?
你可以去古希腊旅游
You could be visiting ancient Greece.
我要怎么去古希腊旅游？
How could I visit ancient Greece?
我懂 因为你怕坐飞机
I get it. Because you're afraid of flying.
不 因为古希腊已经成为过去了
No. Because ancient Greece is in the past.
就像达什
Just like Dash.
好吧 你知道还有谁陷在过去吗？就是你
Okay. You want to know who else is stuck in the past? You are.
你太怕在生活中再次受到伤害
You're so afraid of life hurting you again
所以你就停止了生活
that you've stopped living.
你就像个人类木乃伊
You're like a human mummy.
我不是…
I didn't…
木乃伊就是人类
Mummies are human.
该死的破…我靠
Stupid-- Oh, crap.
真的很抱歉 我会清理干净
I'm so sorry. I will clean this up.
我向你保证 我平时不乱扔垃圾的
I am not a litterer, I assure you that.
能不能麻烦你帮我叫辆车？
Do you think you could call a car for me, please?
谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
把车开过来
Bring the car around.
天啊 这是谁的牙齿保持器吗？
God, is that someone's retainer?
在她面前 我从来说不好话
I've never said the right thing one time around her.
我会紧张 因为她一张口
I get nervous because she opens her mouth,
那就是一部美丽的百科全书
and just an encyclopedia of beautifulness comes out,
而我从来都说不出…
and I just never say--
你知道她打算把我写死吗？
You know she's trying to kill me?
我就想拿一下番茄
I just need those tomatoes.
不 没错 你说得对
You're right. No, you're right.
我应该去道歉 谢了 哥们
I should apologize. Thank you, man.
-非常感谢 -不客气
-I appreciate that very, very much. -You're welcome.
洛蕾塔赛琪 对
Loretta Sage. Yeah.
嗨
Hiya.
我没叫优步拼车
I did not order an UberPool.
有人想见你 很快就送你回来
Someone wants to meet you. We'll have you right back.
洛蕾塔
Loretta!
Loretta! Loretta?
洛蕾塔？
Loretta?
-你说“洛蕾塔”？ -对啊
-Did you say "Loretta"? -Yeah.
-跟着那辆休旅车 老兄 -不
-Follow that SUV, man. -No.
-帮个忙吧！ -不行
-Come on, please! -No, no, no.
我不会再帮陌生帅哥了 吃一堑长一智
I'm not helping any more handsome strangers. Fool me once.
这怎么回事 贩卖人口？我被绑架了吗？
What is this, Taken? Am I "tooken"?
我已经被卖掉了？
Am I sold already?
被卖给这个人了吗？
Am I sold to him?
-停下 -糟了 吓到你了吗？
-Stop. -Oh, no. Did this feel creepy?
我跟你们说过 别搞得那么吓人
I said don't make it creepy, guys.
非常抱歉 这里比较简陋
I'm so sorry about the setting.
我才刚下飞机 要和你见面我特别紧张
I just flew in. I was in a real panic to meet you.
没什么时间来布置
I didn't have time to dress the place up much.
我听说你喜欢奶酪 所以就准备全了
I read you love cheese, so I just got them all.
之前给我发邮件 要我脚丫子照片
Are you the one who's been emailing me
的人就是你吗？
for photos of my feet?
不是
No.
我向你保证 我要给你看的东西
And I promise what I'm about to show you
会让你非常开心
is gonna make you very happy.
但首先 先来介绍一下 你眼前这个神秘的坏蛋
But first, a little bit about the mysterious rogue you see before you.
我叫阿比盖尔费尔法克斯
My name is Abigail Fairfax.
阿比盖尔？
Abigail?
这是个中性名字 就像莱斯利 贝弗利
It's a gender-neutral name, like Leslie or Beverly.
对 但你是那个传媒巨头
Yes, but you're Abigail Fairfax
费尔法克斯家的阿比盖尔？
of the media-mogul Fairfaxes?
你不是刚刚接管了公司吗 还是…
Didn't you just take over your company or…
不 那其实是我弟莱斯利
No, that was my brother, actually.
我们都很为他骄傲
That was Leslie. We're all very proud.
确实是 这么年轻就…
Yes, I should say so, at such a young age to--
甚至会有人认为他太年轻了
Some might even say too young.
但我对那些从来都不感兴趣
But that world never really interested me.
不瞒你说 我所痴迷的
My passions, as you may know,
是世上隐藏的宝物
lie in the hidden things in the world,
那些难以占有的东西
things which defy possession.
我就像一个收藏家
Some might call me a collector.
但有一样东西尤其让我痴迷
But there is one obsession in particular
让我日思夜想
that has held me captive.
火焰皇冠
The Crown of Fire
还有上面层层镶嵌的红色钻石
and its cascading red diamonds.
这是个…隐藏摄像机的恶作剧节目吗？
Is this a… hidden-camera thing?
所以当我发现你新书中
So imagine my surprise when, in your new book,
层层堆彻的性幻想里隐藏的珠玑之语时
amidst the pages of coital reverie,
我的惊讶之情…
was something…
-我的天啊 -…实在是难以附加
-Oh, God. -…quite magnificent.
我懂了 我全明白了
I get it. I get it. I so get it right now.
我的妈呀
Oh, my gosh.
我还真以为你们把我绑架了呢
I literally thought you guys kidnapped me.
这是营销操作对吧？是贝丝安排的吗？
I mean, this is marketing, right? Beth set this up?
你们真是太厉害了 太棒了
This was so good, you guys. This was amazing.
你 拿着枪还留着小胡子
You, with your gun and your mustache
还有那句“你最好乖乖进去” 真是…
and your, "You'd better get in there" and you know…
天啊
Oh, my God.
还有你 一身同色系的特种部队行头
You, with the G.I. Joe tone-on-tone outfit.
你书中虚构的考古学家
Your fictional archaeologist
真的在翻译一种已经灭亡的语言
was making real translations of a dead language.
至今为止还没有其他人能做到
Something nobody else has been able to do.
没有其他人试过
Well, nobody else had ever tried.
对不对？我这么说行吗？
Is that right? Am I saying the right thing?
除了你 对吧？
Except you, right?
除了我
Except me!
对 是这样的
Yes. See, it turns out
洛蕾塔塞琪曾经是一名年轻的女大学生
Loretta Sage was once a young college girl doing her dissertation
她和她未来的丈夫 正在写一篇
on the dead language of the D
关于D城灭亡语言的论文
with her future husband,
她梦想着有朝一日 能找到卡拉曼的
dreaming of finding Kalaman's tomb
陵墓和火焰皇冠
and the Crown of Fire.
我听说在他死后 你放弃了这个梦想 我很遗憾
I was sorry to read you gave up your search after he died.
但这就意味着
But what that means is,
你是我唯一的希望
you're all I have left.
你希望做什么？
All you have left for… what?
给你看吧
Here we go.
这是什么？
What is this?
我相信这上面描述了 卡拉曼陵墓的确切位置
I believe it is describing the exact location of Kalaman's tomb,
塔哈和她珍贵的头饰就埋葬在那里
in which Taha and her priceless headdress are buried.
就算这是真的
Well, if this were authentic,
你还得把整座城挖出来才行
you would still have to uncover an entire city
没人知道那座城在哪里
that nobody has been able to find.
我找到了
I found it.
就在洪迪达岛 大西洋中一座与世隔绝的小岛
On a tiny, forgotten island in the Atlantic called Isla Hundida.
但我找不到的是卡拉曼最后的安息之处
What I have not been able to find is Kalaman's final resting place.
这张羊皮纸 是我们在遗迹中找到的唯一线索
This piece of parchment is the only clue we found among the ruins.
我需要一个能破译这些符号的人
I need someone who can decipher these symbols.
我需要你
I need you.
-这… -塞琪女士
-Well… -Miss Sage,
你肯定不希望你的故事就这么完结
surely this isn't how you want your story to end.
我们俩的梦想都因为厄运而破灭
We both had our dreams crushed by bad luck,
或者就我而言 是因为一个马屁精弟弟
or in my case, an arse-kissing little brother,
但这是我们向世人证明自己的机会
but this is our chance to show them all.
和我一起前往这个小岛
Come with me… to the island.
破译这些符号 帮助我找到火焰皇冠
Translate these symbols and help me find the Crown of Fire.
你可以开个价
You can name your price.
我不能接受 抱歉
I must respectfully decline.
好吧
Well…
我承认我很失望
I can't say I'm not disappointed.
但我理解你的感受
But I understand how you feel.
至少让我们送你一程可以吗？
Will you at least let us give you a ride?
不用了 谢谢 我会自己叫车 我就…
No, thank you. I'll call for my own car, and I'll just…
我觉得你没有在听我说
I don't feel like you're listening to me.
这事很紧急 而且我们…
This is urgent, and we--
好 警察说他们已经发布了全境通…
Okay, so the police are saying that they put out an APB…
-全境通缉令 -…缉捕一辆休旅车
-APB. -…on an SUV,
然后有个24小时的规定 所以…
and there's this 24-hour rule…
-为什么还有规定？-…他们目前没法…
- Why is there a rule? - …and they won't do anything until…
那联邦调查局和中央情报局呢？
What about the FBI or the CIA?
-他们让找警察 -洛蕾塔肯定没事
-They said to call the police. -I'm sure Loretta's fine.
我上大学时 我朋友尼基“失踪”了
When I was in college, my friend Nicki went missing.
大家都急坏了
Everyone was freaking out.
但后来发现她就在自己车里
But then she was just in her car.
她死了 但我们找到了她 并没有失踪
She was dead, but we found her. She wasn't gone.
那…我们找个私家侦探怎么样？
What about… Maybe we could get a PI
或者私营保安公司什么的 或者…
or, like, you know, private security or--
营救队怎么样 就像电影里演的？
What about an extraction team, like the movie?
但谁干这行？退伍军人对吧？
But who does that? The ex-military, right?
对了 我想我认识一个可以帮上忙的人
Oh, yeah. I think I actually have somebody that could help us.
我参加过一个冥想静修 那里有个教官
I did this meditation retreat, and there was this trainer guy there.
你真该看看他冥想时的样子
You should see this guy meditate.
他以前是海军陆战队的
But he's ex-Navy SEAL.
他是特种部队的教官 叫什么来着？
He's a special ops trainer. What was his name?
对了 杰克教官
Yeah. Jack Trainer.
这位教官的名字叫“杰克教官”？
So he's a trainer named Jack Trainer?
我手机里就是这么存人名的
That's how I have everybody in my phone.
你看 “贾妮思老妈”
See, "Janice Mom."
“拉瑞炮王” “斯黛茜小菊花”
"Larry Doorknob." "Stacy Butt Stuff."
看 他就是干这行的 专门找人
Look, this is what this guy does. He finds people.
如果这世上有谁能帮我们的话 那就是他了
If there's anybody that can help us, it's him.
-杰克教官 -原来他真的姓“教官”
-Jack Trainer. -So his name is actually Jack Trainer.
嗨 我是艾伦
Hi, this is Alan
我们在“触摸你的内在自我”上见过的
from "Touching Your Inner Self."
那个冥想静修？
The meditation retreat?
好吧 是这样的 我们的朋友洛蕾塔被绑架了
Anyway, okay. Our friend Loretta has been kidnapped,
没有人肯帮我们
and no one's helping us.
她失踪多久了？
How long she been missing?
差不多两小时
Maybe two hours now.
这是哪位？
Who is that?
这是贝丝 我是贝丝
This is Beth. I'm Beth.
还有艾莉森 先生
And Allison is on too, sir.
她有没有带什么能联网的设备？
Did she have any Wi-Fi-enabled devices?
-她带手机了吧？ -没有 她的手机在我这儿
-She's got her phone, right? -No, I have her phone.
她戴了块智能手表 之前把我的假发勾掉的
She has a smartwatch. It ripped my wig off.
那是什么情况？算了 当我没问 把手机打开
What was that scenario? Never mind. Open the phone.
-点开智能手表应用 -好的
-Go to the smartwatch app. -All right.
然后点“查找我的智能手表”
Then hit "Find My Smartwatch."
天啊 太好了 这通电话真是打对了
Oh, my… That is so good. That's why we called.
“天下难事 必作于易”
"Anticipate the difficult by managing the easy."
-是奥普拉还是狄帕克？ -老子 《道德经》
-Is that Oprah or Deepak? -Laozi from Tao-te Ching.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
她在大西洋
It's in the Atlantic.
-她在飞机上？ -你怎么知道？
-She's on a plane? -How can you tell that?
因为游泳游不了那么快
'Cause she can't swim that fast.
看来不是赎金类
Doesn't sound like a ransom scenario.
我猜是血腥体育类 《饥饿游戏》那种情况
My guess is blood sport, Hunger Games-type situation.
可能是暗网上以毒品为目的的寻宝游戏
Possibly some coke-fueled dark web scavenger hunt.
乱得很 我们必须抓紧时间
Real clown shit. We'll have to move fast.
我们该怎么付你报酬？
How do we pay you?
加密货币 移动支付应用
Cryptocurrency. Cash App.
我会在48小时内救她回来
I'll have her back within 48 hours
否则下次救援不收钱
or your next rescue is free.
有多少人需要下次救援？
How many people need a next rescue?
超乎你的想象
More than you'd think.
-我需要她的手机 -我送来给你
-I'm gonna need that phone. -I'll bring it to you.
把她的着陆地点告诉我 我们去那里会合 艾伦
Let me know where she lands. I'll meet you there, Alan.
你醒啦
Hello.
这是什么地方？
Where am I?
这是我的飞机上
You're on my plane.
很不错吧？
It's nice, isn't it?
座椅是用驼妈妈的皮做的
The seats are made of mama llama leather.
我要下飞机
Well, I'm getting off your plane.
给我松绑
Unchain me!
那是安全带
That's your seat belt.
你用氯仿麻醉我？ 居然还真有人这么做？
Did you chloroform me? People actually do that?
经典手段嘛 总是有道理的
Well, you know, it's a classic for a reason.
我的身体就像喝醉了一样
My body feels drunk.
等会儿就好了 真对不起
It'll wear off in a bit. I am sorry.
但我没时间等你改变主意
I just couldn't wait around for you to change your mind.
-不许软趴趴 -我们的时间很紧
-Stop playing jelly. -Time is not on our side.
挖掘现场中心的火山
The volcano we're excavating around
最近开始严重消化不良
has developed a bad case of indigestion.
我非常担心一旦火山爆发
I'm rather worried that when it blows,
迷失之城里剩下的一切就要灰飞烟灭了
everything that's left of the Lost City will be destroyed.
天啊 我的腿不能动
Oh, my God. My legs don't work.
所以这是我们找到陵墓和皇冠的最后机会
So, this is our last chance to find both the tomb and the crown.
天啊
Oh, God.
别怕 只是到达目的地 飞机着陆而已
Don't worry. That's just our final descent.
但是你此生最伟大的冒险才刚刚开始
But it is the beginning of the greatest adventure of your life.
欢迎来到迷失之城
Welcome to the Lost City.
你怎么找到这里的？
How did you find it?
这座城建在一座熔岩穹丘上
So, the city was built on a lava dome.
火山变得活跃以后 穹丘内充满了熔岩
As the volcano became active, the dome filled with lava,
于是沉底的东西就浮上了表面
and sunken things rose to the surface.
D城就出现了
The D exposed itself.
-整座城？ -不 只有顶部
-The entire city? -No, no. Just the tip.
我一听说关于遗迹的传闻
As soon as I heard rumors of the ruins,
就飞过来买下了这地方
I flew over and bought the place.
-挖掘现场？ -不 这座岛
-The site? -No. The island.
朝南的一半 价格很优惠
The southern half. I got a good deal
因为岩浆都往这边流
'cause this is where the lava flows.
挖掘工作已经进行了一年
We've been excavating for a year now.
没人会第一天就绑架言情小说家
One doesn't kidnap a romance novelist on day one.
对 俗话说嘛
Yes, as the saying goes.
拉菲不喜欢这样 是吧 拉菲？
Rafi doesn't like it. Do you, Rafi?
他说我们不尊重他祖先的遗产
He says we're disrespecting his heritage.
但这岛上没什么其他的就业机会 对吧 拉菲？
But not a lot of other job options on the island, are there, Rafi?
要饭的哪能挑肥拣瘦
Beggars can't be choosers.
看来这次没有熟食冷盘了
No more charcuterie, I take it.
拜托 我又不是禽兽
Please. I'm not a monster.
你有什么需要尽管开口
Whatever you need, just shout.
留一只手不要绑 她还得做翻译呢
Leave one hand free. She has some translating to do.
那之后呢？
And then what?
洛蕾塔 我真的希望你能意识到
Loretta, I really wish you would try and see
这对我们而言是一个多么振奋人心的机会
what an exciting opportunity this is for us.
我相信这段文字描述的 就是陵墓的确切地点
I believe this text describes the exact location of the tomb.
这是一种语素文字
It's a logographic system.
就像楔形文字或者象形文字
Like cuneiform or hieroglyphics.
如果你有其他文字材料 能让我做对比的话…
Now, if you have other documents that possibly I can compare…
没有别的了
Yeah, no luck there.
我们在附近的一个瀑布发现了些刻痕
We found some scratching at a nearby waterfall,
但没什么用处
but it was useless.
就是些女人图
Just pictures of women.
听着 我也希望 你亲爱的考古学家老公没死
Look, I, too, wish your dear old dead archaeologist husband
能来帮忙 但他不能 所以
was here to help, but he's not, so,
洛蕾塔 小黄书作者 该你大显身手了
time to shine, Loretta, sex-book writer.
他们会来救我的
They will come for me.
“他们”是谁？
Who, exactly?
你的那群猫咪？
Your many cats?
我没有养猫
I don't have cats.
那就更可悲了
Somehow even more sad.
我养了只仓鼠 王八蛋
I have a hamster, asshole!
你养了只仓鼠王八蛋？
You have a hamster's asshole?
不 那里有个逗号的…算了
No, there was a comma between-- Forget it.
我敢打赌你弟弟从来不用绑架人
I bet your brother never had to kidnap anyone!
见到你真好 兄弟
Good to see you, man.
-手机 -对
-Phone. -Right.
干什么？
What?
我在想 我可以跟你一起去
Yeah, I was thinking that I could maybe just sort of come with you.
-为什么？ -帮忙啊
-Why? -To help.
我会做心肺复苏 会几招拳脚工夫
I know CPR. I know some light karate.
还有混合健身认证
CrossFit certified.
好吧 听我说
Okay, listen, listen!
我…这是我的错
I just-- It's my fault.
不是指绑架什么的
Not the kidnapping and stuff,
但我之前对她说了很苛刻的话 我后悔了
but I said some really mean stuff to her, and I regret it,
我得把话收回
and I just need to take it back.
我说她是人类木乃伊
I called her a human mummy.
木乃伊就是人类
Mummies are human.
我现在知道了
I'm aware of that now, yes.
的确是这样
That is true.
求你了
Please.
好吧 艾伦 我没法对你负责
All right, Alan, I can't be responsible for you.
行 好的
Okay. Yeah.
-你得待在车里 -好
-I need you to stay in the car. -Yeah.
-待在车里 -待在车里
-In the car. -In the car.
-自始至终 -自始至终？
-The whole time. -The whole time?
自始至终
Whole time.
太好了
Yes!
是这辆
This is me.
真的吗？海军陆战队就开这种车？
Really? Is this what the SEAL teams use?
“只有傻瓜才会凭颜色选坐骑”
"Only a fool chooses a horse by its color."
对 《道德经》？
Right, right. The Tao-te Ching?
不 那边租车行牌子上写的
No, it was on the sign back there at the rental place.
谢谢
Thank you.
怎么了？
What? What?
我本想邀请你去吃早饭
I was hoping to invite you to breakfast,
但你好像还有活儿要干
but it looks like you still have work to do.
等等
Wait, wait, wait.
等一下
Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
我相信这里说的是
I believe this says
“安息” 或者“安息的”
"rest" or "resting."
所以这句话可能是 “卡拉曼和他的珍宝…”
So it would be, "Kalaman and his treasure…"
之后缺了一些 然后是“安息” “安息的”
And then there are some missing pieces, and then "rest," "resting,"
还有“眼泪”什么的 对…
and something about "tears," so…
在哪里安息？
Resting where?
上面没说 没有说
Didn't say. It doesn't say.
塞琪女士 你得加把劲才行
Miss Sage, I need you to do better.
那要不你下次 就别绑架言情小说家了 嗯？
Then next time maybe don't kidnap a romance novelist, hmm?
该死 这就不该有多难！
My God, this shouldn't be this hard!
我们找的又不是贫民的坟墓
It is not some pauper's grave we're looking for.
这是一位伟人的纪念碑
It is a monument to a great man!
卡拉曼国王雄心勃勃 力量强大
King Kalaman was ambitious, he was powerful,
他是第一个在大西洋上建立了一座城的人
he was the first man to build a city in the Atlantic.
他的臣民会对他翘首仰望
The eyes of his subjects would have turned to him.
他会用一座金字塔 神塔
He would have had a pyramid, a ziggurat,
一座高塔来存放他的火焰皇冠
a tower to hold his Crown of Fire.
我只需要知道地点
All I need to know is where it is.
不知你还记不记得 但你只说过让我翻译
I don't know if you recall, but you only said translate it.
我翻译好了
I translated it.
再翻一遍
Translate it again.
以后说起这件事 我们会当作笑谈的
One day, we're gonna laugh about this.
多么奇妙的冒险
Such an adventure we're having.
我该跟你一起去 就当是支援 而且带上我更棒
I should go with you, just for backup and awesomeness.
这已经很棒了
This is pretty awesome.
有大自然 无线电
You got nature, the radio.
对 说得对 但对我来说异常重要的一点
Yeah, you're right, but it's very, very important to me
就是她得知道我来救她了
that she knows that I came to rescue her.
怎么 你喜欢她？
Why? Do you like this woman?
不 我就是带了零食什么的
No, I just brought snacks and stuff.
她一肚子饿就会发脾气
She gets a little grumpy when she's hungry.
血压下降 我懂的
Blood pressure drops. And I get that
因为我自己一天要吃五顿饭
because I'm a five-meal-a-day kind of guy.
对了 你生酮饮食吗？看上去像
Do you keto, by the way? You look like you keto.
-没有 -没有 好吧
-No. -No. Yeah.
-你不需要 -怎么回事？
-You don't need it. -What is it?
我只想让她不要只把我当作一个封面模特
I just want her to think of me as more than a cover model.
但是 艾伦 你远不止如此
But, Alan, you are so much more.
你是帮我望风的伙伴
You're my lookout.
好吧 能不能至少让我扶她坐进车里
Okay, can I at least do the part where I put her in the car
然后说：“嘘 你现在安全了”？
and I just go, "Shh. You're safe now"?
当然了 老弟 她肯定会喜欢的
Sure, champ. She'll love that.
你这就走了？开始了？
Oh, you're just going? Going to start?
你这就开始行动了？好吧
You're starting the mission now? Okay.
睡吧
Go to sleep.
-艾伦 -干吗？
-Alan. -What?
你辜负了我的信任 艾伦
This is a breach of trust, Alan.
我可以帮上忙 让我帮忙吧
I can help. Let me help.
跟紧点 保住小命
Stay close. Stay alive.
嘿
Hey.
睡吧
Go to sleep.
我接住他的头了
I got his head.
怎么处理他的头？我让他躺下好了
What do I do with his head? I'm just gonna set him down.
别
No.
喂 不！
Hey, hey, no!
不！
No, no, no!
厉害呀
Ooh, yeah!
团队合作 真好！
Teamwork, yeah!
你很努力 艾伦 但那人已经晕了
Great effort, Alan, but that man was already unconscious.
我刚没收住
I was already wound up.
下次别再…
Just don't do it when I'm…
嗨
Hi.
7点钟方向
On your seven!
教官 他还没睡
Trainer, he's not asleep!
别爬起来
Stay down. Stay down.
-你做得很好 -谢谢
-You're doing great. -Thanks.
你去哪儿？
Where you going?
啥？
What?
洛蕾塔塞琪？
Loretta Sage?
是我
Yes.
我是来救你的
I'm getting you out of here.
-你怎么这么帅？ -我爸以前是个天气预报员
-Why are you so handsome? -My dad was a weatherman.
艾伦？
Alan?
-是我 -你怎么在这里？
-Yeah. -What are you doing here?
-无论所谓 我是来救你的 -那不是…
-Irregardless, I'm here to save you. -That's not…
-他想说的应该是“无论如何” -对
-I think he meant "regardless." -Yes.
她那里需要你救吗 教官？ 我觉得她挺好的
Does she need saving in there, Trainer? I think she's fine there.
不 别拿他们的东西 他们会追来的
No, leave it. Don't take their stuff. They'll come after us.
艾伦 你干吗总这样？
Alan, why do you keep doing that?
你干吗总这样？我已经搞定了
Why do you keep doing that? I had that one.
这样做不厚道 没有必要
It's just getting mean now. It's unnecessary.
对不起 我就是想揍一拳
I'm sorry. I just wanted to get one in.
不好意思 能不能帮我松个绑？
Excuse me. Would it be possible to remove me from the chair?
-来不及 -来不及？
-No time. -No time?
刚才光顾着聊天了
There's been so much chitchat.
我们得赶快走
We should definitely go.
快！
Let's go! Let's go!
怎么会发生爆炸？
Why are things exploding?
我来…
I got--
好了
Okay.
嘘…
Shh…
嘘 你现在安全了
Shh. You're safe now.
你现…
You're…
你怎么这么镇定？
How are you so calm?
-那应该是我说的 -来
-That was my line. -Here.
-干吗呢？ -这是灵气疗法吗？
-What? -Is that Reiki?
-你在医治我吗？ -我想是的
-Are you healing me? -I think so.
老子说过：“清静…”
As Laozi says, "To the mind that is still…"
“…为天下正”
"…the whole universe surrenders."
我也会说适合这个场合的名人名言
Yeah, I know some quotes that could be good for this moment.
印诺尼亚帕拉特斯
In omnia paratus.
“随时做好一切准备”
"Ready for anything."
这样含情脉脉地相互注视不太好吧
Maybe we shouldn't be just staring lovingly into each other's eyes
就像要坠入爱河似的 我还在旁边呢
like you're gonna fall in love like I'm not here.
你是谁？
Who are you?
一个努力完成任务的人
Just a guy trying to do his job.
而现在的任务就是把这位美丽的女士…
Right now, that job is to get this lovely lady--
我的天啊
Oh, God. Okay.
怎么回事？
What is happening?
我们该怎么办？
Okay. What do we do?
我们得…我都看不清了
We need to do-- I can't see.
我不喜欢这样
I don't like it!
给你
Here. Here!
-你怎么扔枪啊？ -搞什么？
-Why would you throw a gun? -Seriously?
-快帮我松绑 -不行 来不及了
-Get me out of the chair. -I can't. We don't have time.
挤一挤 快做个凯格尔运动什么的
Gotta squeeze! You got to do a Kegel or something!
-快点凯啊 -你以为凯格尔运动是什么？
-Kegel it! -What do you think a Kegel is?
我还没进来 还是没进来
I'm not in it, not in! Still not in!
-你得再进去一点 -停 停下
-You got to go in more. -Stop. Stop. Stop it!
天啊 快上车 开车 快开啊
Oh, God. Get in the car, get in the car! Start the car! Start the car!
-快 -把腿挪开
-Go, go. -Move your leg.
-哪条？ -两条都挪开
-Which one? -Both of them! Move them!
-向前开 -好
-Forward, forward! -Okay. Okay.
-好了 这就开 -快开啊
-I'm going! I'm going! Okay! -Drive!
嘘 你现在安全了 嘘
Shh. You're safe now. Shh.
-嘘 你现在安全了 -不 没有 我不安全
-Shh. You're safe now. -No, I'm not. Not safe.
糟了 我在流血吗？
Oh, no, am I bleeding?
-应该不是你的血 -好多血
-I don't think that's yours. -That's a lot of blood.
老天爷啊
Cheese and rice!
-这是他的脑浆吗？ -什么？
-Are those his brains? -What?
他的脑浆好像迸我脸上了
I think his brains are on my face!
我嘴里肯定有他的脑浆 我能尝到他的思想
Definitely his brains are in my mouth. I can taste his thoughts!
专心开车
Focus on the road.
他只是喜欢当教官而已 教官
He just liked training people. Trainer.
-你说什么呢？ -他对我情深义重
-What are you talking about? -He loved me.
你能不能靠左开？
Can you just scooch the car over to the left?
-擦掉 快擦掉 -天啊
-Get it off. Get it off. -Oh, God.
当心！
Watch out!
你刚看到…
Did you see…
不
No.
不会的
Oh, no. Oh, no.
不
Oh, no.
艾伦？
Alan?
哎呀妈呀 你没事吧？
Oh, holy Christmas. Are you okay? Are you okay?
你能不能帮我松绑？
Do you think you could get me out of here?
好
Yeah. Okay.
-你从车里飞出来了 -是的 的确是
-You just flew out of the car. -I did. I did, indeed.
好 有我在
Okay. I got you. I got you.
你能把我松开吗？从椅子上松开
Can you get me out of the chair? Get me out of the chair.
对 说得对
You're right. You're right. You're right.
-那是指甲锉吗？ -是的
-Is that a nail filer? -Yeah.
-你不能直接扯吗？ -快锉开了
-Can you just rip it? -It's working.
下次我再扔枪给你
And maybe next time I toss a gun at you,
你能不能接住不要躲？
you can catch it instead of ducking.
下次你再扔枪给我
How about the next time you toss a gun at me,
能不能说一句：“艾伦 接住”？
you say, "Hey, Alan, catch"?
能不能扔之前先说？
Then maybe do that before you throw it?
“给你”和“接住”是近义词
Well, "here" is a synonym for "catch."
不 “给你”和“接住”不是“近词”
No, "here" is not a cinnamon for "catch."
在口语中是一个意思
In a colloquial kind of way, yes, it is.
我说“给你” 扔件运动衫给你
You say, "Here," I toss you a sweatshirt.
我说“给你” 扔支笔给你
You say, "Here," I toss you a pen.
为什么不能就说：“喂！接住！枪！”
How 'bout just, "Hey! Catch! Gun!"
无论你要扔什么
Anything that you want to throw,
我都会接住 因为你说了“接住”
I'll catch it because you said, "Catch."
我会接住 因为你让我接住
And I'll catch it because you said it.
这么说也是可以的
That is also an option,
这样的话我们就有一把枪了
and then we would have a gun with us.
就这么回事
That's a thing.
-小心 -好 我们得联络…
-Be careful. -Okay, we need to call--
小心点
Be careful.
我们得打电话求救 前往机场 然后离开这里
We need to call for help, get to the airport and get out of here.
-这次我开车 -好
-And I am driving. -Okay.
好吧 快打电话求助
Okay, call for help.
你的电话呢？
Where's your phone?
好吧
Okay.
-快说你抓住他们了 -干掉了金发那个
-Tell me you caught them. -I tagged the blond one.
洛蕾塔
Loretta.
你到底怎么想的？
What are you thinking?
你们或许是杀了他们其中一个
You might've killed one of them,
但她的搭档还和她在一起
but his partner's still with her.
他显然武艺高强 训练有素
And he is clearly skilled, highly trained
并且非常危险
and very dangerous.
所以说 塞琪女士说她要离开活动现场
So, Miss Sage said she was gonna leave the event,
然后她上了一辆车 离开了活动现场？
then got in a car and left the event?
-你们试过给她打电话了吗？ -她没带手机
-Did you try calling her? -She doesn't have her phone.
-手机被盗 -我可没这么说
-Stolen phone. -Didn't say that.
我的放大镜哪去了？
Where's my magnifier?
你能帮一下我奶奶吗？
Listen, can you please help with Nana?
我不想让她知道洛蕾塔的事 她会担心的
I don't want her hearing about Loretta 'cause it's going to upset her.
洛蕾塔出什么事了？
What about Loretta?
没事 奶奶 她只是去旅游了
Nothing, Nana. She just went on a trip.
-很好 -是啊
-Good. -Yeah.
那姑娘的确该出去走走
That girl needed to get out of the house.
好 是这样的
So, this is the thing.
洛蕾塔的电话没有被盗 是我拿的
Loretta's phone is not stolen. I took it.
我把电话给了艾伦
I gave it to Alan.
艾伦又给了那位教官 杰克教官
Alan then gave it to the trainer, Jack Trainer.
我们就是这样找到她的智能手表的
And that is how we found her wearable.
-艾伦是谁？ -达什
-And who's Alan? -Dash.
-那是什么？ -他是她所有小说中的英雄人物
-What's that? -He's the hero in all of her books.
奶奶
Nana.
-喂 贱人 -别
-Hey, slut. -Mm-mmm.
我们去隔壁房间
Let's go in the other room
聊聊你经历过的战争吧
and talk about whichever war you lived through.
来吧 会很有意思的 抱歉 会很有意思的
Okay. Come on, it'll be fun. I'm sorry. It'll be fun.
听着 洛蕾塔塞琪失踪了
Listen, Loretta Sage is missing.
我查找她的智能手表时
When I looked at her smartwatch,
上面显示她已经飞到了
it said that she had flown
一个我从没听说过的小岛上
to some island I've never even heard about.
所以你们必须采取行动
That means y'all need to do something about this.
否则我就亲自动手 那样你们就会脸上无光
And if you can't, I will, and that won't look good for you.
我很确定这超出了我们的管辖范围
Pretty sure that's outside our jurisdiction.
你得去找联邦调查局
You'd have to call the Feds.
好吧
Okay.
要是你真找了联邦调查局 请你替我美言几句
And if you do go to the Feds, put in a good word for me.
-还有我 -替我们俩
-For me. -For us.
你打算怎么做？把车重新拼起来？
What are you gonna do, put the car back together?
这…我们可以…
Well… we could…
你刚说手机在哪儿来着？
Where did you say the phone was?
副驾杂物箱
Passenger glove.
-什么？ -副驾杂物箱里
-What? -Passenger glove compartment.
天啊
Goodness.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
天啊 没有手机 没有汽车 我们会死在…
Oh, my God. No phone, no car. We're so gonna die out--
-给你 -这是什么？
-Here. -What is this?
丛林里走路用的靴子
Boots for the jungle.
虽然并不是走路用的靴子 但…
It's not exactly hiking boots, but…
我就想着你穿了这么长时间高跟鞋
I figured your feet would be killing you
脚肯定很疼
after wearing heels for this long.
只找到了这双 是艾莉森的 抱歉
It was the best we could do. They're Allison's. Sorry.
行 谢谢你
Okay, well, thank you.
给 我带了奶酪
Here, I got you cheese.
-太好了 -你必须补充水份
-Oh, my God. -You got to stay hydrated.
-太感谢了 -他们没有玻璃瓶的
-Thank you so much. -They didn't have glass bottles,
所以喝完以后得带去回收
so we'll definitely hold onto it and recycle.
好 我们要做的就是 找一部电话
So, what we need to do is find a phone,
联络相关部门
we need to call the authorities,
然后在这里等待救援
and we need to wait here until somebody comes and rescues us.
这…这就是救援
This… This is the rescue.
没有其他人会来
No one else is coming.
-你说什么？ -我就是救援
-I'm sorry? -I'm the rescue.
本来就是我一个人
It was originally just gonna be me,
然后我觉得 应该带上教官
then I was like, Trainer should come.
教官 愿你安息
Oh, Trainer. Rest in peace.
所以我们的最佳选择是前往机场
So, our best bet is to get to the airport.
看到这条路了吗？
See this road right here?
从这里开始 抄近路穿过丛林直达公路
From this area, just take a shortcut through the jungle to the road.
你刚说“穿过丛林”？
Did you just say "shortcut through the jungle"?
-对 -好 你看到我们俩了吗？
-Yeah. -Okay, do you see us?
你不是达什 我不是洛芙摩尔 好吗？
You are not Dash, and I'm not Lovemore. Okay?
我是洛蕾塔 你是艾伦
I'm Loretta, and you are Alan.
-丛林会把我们这种人生吞活剥的 -还吃人呢
-And jungles eat people like us, okay? -Eat people.
而且我不想把这件衣服弄坏
And I don't want to mess up the jumpsuit.
是租来的 所以我们就待在这里
It's on loan. So we're gonna stay put.
我们不能在这里傻站着
We're not just gonna stand around here.
我们要穿过丛林
We're gonna go through the jungle,
我们要前往机场 然后找一部电话
we're gonna go to the airport and find a phone,
这样鱼和蛋糕就都有了
so you can have your cake and get what you want.
“蛋糕” 拿来吃吗？
"And eat it too"?
你想吃就吃 我们走吧
If that's what you want to do with your cake, fine. Let's go.
-蛋糕只能拿来吃 -对我不是
-That's the only thing you do with cake. -Not mine.
我不知道你拿蛋糕做什么 但我们是拿来吃的
I don't know what your people do, but my people eat it.
你可以当作礼物送人
You could give it to someone as a gift.
送了人 人家也是要吃掉的
Those people are still going to eat the cake.
所有人都吃蛋糕
Everybody eats cake.
那些藏在蛋糕里的人呢？
What about the kind people jump out of?
他们藏在里面的时候就不吃
They don't eat it, when they're in it.
老天爷啊
Oh, my God.
他们到底为什么绑架你？
What did they kidnap you for anyhow?
是《飓风营救》里那种奇怪的性交易吗？
Is it some weird sex stuff like Taken?
天啊 谢谢
Oh, my God, thank you.
我本来也这么以为 但那人是费尔法克斯家的
I thought so too, but the guy's one of the Fairfaxes.
-贝弗利？ -不 他哥
-Beverly? -No, the older one.
那个拍视频博客 找蒙特祖玛宝藏的怪人
The really odd one that had the vlog on finding Montezuma's treasure.
就是新闻上播的
The dude that was on the news
那个要打捞泰坦尼克的家伙？
for trying to raise the Titanic?
对 他在找火焰皇冠
Yes, he's looking for the Crown of Fire.
等一下 你是指真正的火焰皇冠？就像…
Wait a minute. Like the actual Crown of Fire? Like the one…
-所以说那个遗迹是… -迷失之城D 对
-So those ruins were-- -They were the Lost City of D, yes.
什么？你在开玩笑吗？
What? Are you kidding me right now?
这和你书里写的一样
This is like your book.
所以说我们现在基本就是
So we're basically on like a
像洛芙摩尔和达什一样在冒险？
Lovemore and Dash adventure right now?
什么东西？
What is that?
万一费尔法克斯真找到皇冠呢？
What if Fairfax actually finds the crown?
不会 他不会的
He won't. He won't.
往哪边？
Where do we go?
好 我们得下水去
Okay, we need to get in the water.
-什么？ -我们得沿着河走
-What? -We need to go by river.
不行 我不喜欢碰水
No, I don't really do water.
什么叫“不喜欢碰水”？
What do you mean, "do water"?
又不是叫你和它结婚生子
I'm not asking you to procreate with it.
我的身体和水八字不合
My body and water don't really go together.
那你是想死吗？
How do you feel about dying?
哎呀
Oh, God.
没事了 有我在
You're okay. You're okay. I got you. I got you.
-我能游泳 -行
-I can swim. I can swim. -Fine.
-你去哪儿？ -我在渡河
-Where are you going? -I'm crossing.
不 我们得待在水里
No, we have to stay in the water.
我写《荒野中的一年》时 研究过
I researched aquatic counter-tracking for my book,
水中反跟踪术
A Year in the Bush.
下了水 他们就没法追踪了
They'll lose our tracks in the water.
这里为什么是热的？等等 你尿尿了吗？
Why is it warm here? Wait, are you peeing?
你绕过去好了
Just go around it.
好吧 我觉得…
Okay, I think…
应该甩掉他们了吧？
I think we lost them, right?
对 还算不赖
Yeah. That wasn't so bad. Yeah.
好
Okay.
-不要慌 -什么叫“不要慌”？
-Don't panic. -What do you mean, don't panic?
-就别慌 -不
-Just don't panic. -No.
别再说“慌”这个字了 我已经慌了
Stop saying "panic." I'm panicking now.
你的背上有东西
You have something on your back.
不！
No!
-不要叫 -是什么？
-Stop screaming. -What is that?
-什么东西？ -别叫了
-What is that? -Stop screaming.
-你身上有吗？ -没有
-Do you have any on you? -No. No.
你身上为什么没有？
Why don't you have any on you?
可能这衣服把它们吓跑了 我也不知道
Maybe the jumpsuit scared them off. I don't know.
-帮我弄掉 -我的天啊
-Get them off. -Oh, my God.
不行 我不能碰这些满是血 黏糊糊的小袋子
Okay. No, I can't touch those blood-gorged mucous sacks.
-你自己弄行吗？ -快点
-Can you fling it? -Right now.
-快弄掉 -你自己抓了扔掉
-Get it. -Just pick it and fling it.
-抓了扔掉 -要抓你抓！
-Just pick it and fling it. -You pick it and fling it!
-能转圈子甩掉吗？ -快帮我弄掉
-Can you spin it off? -Please, get it off.
我不想碰 我头好晕
I don't like touching it. I'm feeling faint.
-它们要把我的灵魂吸走了 -好 别这样
-They're sucking my soul out. -Okay, okay. Stop, stop, stop.
别发出这种声音
Don't make that sound.
有几条？
How many of them are there?
不是很多
There's not many.
我感觉有好多
It feels like there's so many.
感觉好多
I feel so many.
-我的上帝呀 -你祷什么告啊？
-Holy mother of God! -Why are you praying?
有那么严重吗 不可能吧 很糟糕吗 有几条？
Is it that bad? It can't be that bad. Is it that bad? How many?
情况不是很妙
It's not great.
它们要把我吸干了
They're gonna suck every bit of me out.
拜托你别说话了 我得蹲下来 等一下
Please stop speaking. I just need to get low. Hold on a second.
天啊！我能感觉到它们吸得好多
Oh, God! I can feel them just sucking out so much.
等它们完事 我就成一挂干瘪的人皮袋了
I'm gonna be a shriveled-up skin sack when they're done.
别告诉我爸我是这么死的
You cannot tell my dad I died this way.
你得说我是和巨蟒搏斗战死的
You gotta tell him I was wrestling an anaconda
还手持宝剑什么的
with a sword or something.
我就像一瓶人血鲜果汁 它们要把我吸光光
I'm like a blood Jamba Juice. They're just sucking it all out.
不过为什么都在我屁股上？
Why are they all on my butt though?
这和我平时从色拉里挑掉小咸鱼有点像
Kind of like picking anchovies off my Caesar salad.
-其实也还好 -小咸鱼？
-It's actually not so bad. -Anchovies?
这种时候提吃的东西做什么？
Why do you go to food right now?
找到那条皇后 快点搞定
Just find the queen, and let's be done with this.
应该可以了 我得看看你前面有没有
Think you're good. I just need to check your front.
好 我不敢看
Okay. I can't look.
很糟吗？
Is it bad?
-哇哦 -怎么了？你就直说吧
-Wow. -What is it? Just say it.
你意料到会…不是…
I mean, you expect it to, you know, not…
然后突然间看到了…
Then suddenly there it is, and…
-那个…你为某个人感到兴奋 -什么？
-You know, you get excited for a person. -What?
-我为所有人感到兴奋 -你兴奋什么？
-I mean, I'm excited for all people. -Why are you excited?
是这样的 人们会好奇 会想知道
Well, you know, people wonder, they wonder,
但他们并不知道 对吧？
but they don't know, right?
他们不知道 直到他们突然间知道了
They don't, until suddenly they do know,
然后他们就知道了之前不知道的事
and then they know something that wasn't known before.
我身上到底还有没有蚂蟥了？
Just do I have any leeches or not?
你的勇士形单影只地挂着
Your plucky warrior hangs in tranquil solitude.
什么？
What?
没有了 你没事了
No, you're good. You're good.
我们刚刚真勇敢 它们为什么那么爱吸屁股？
We were so brave just then. Why do they go for the butt so much?
你唱什么呢？
What's that song you're singing?
我小时候外婆唱给我听的歌
A song my abbi used to sing to me when I was a kid.
-“如果你吸岛的生命…” -嗯？
-"If you suck life from the island… -Yeah?
“…岛就会吸你的”
…the island will suck of you."
你外婆给你唱被岛吸的歌？
Your grandma sang you songs about getting sucked off by an island?
翻译过来意思就不对了
It doesn't translate super well.
有幻觉蚂蟥综合征这回事吗？
Is phantom leech syndrome a thing?
它们不下蛋吧？
They don't lay eggs, do they?
塔哈王后？
Queen Taha?
“卡拉曼国王和他的珍宝安息在…
"King Kalaman and his treasure laid to rest…
安息在无尽的眼泪之井中
laid to rest in the well of endless tears.
安息在无尽的眼泪之井中”
Laid to rest in the well of endless tears."
-是什么意思呢？ -洛蕾塔
-What does that mean? -Loretta!
差点被你吓死
You gave me a heart attack.
你跑哪去了？
Where'd you go?
这是什么？
What is this?
我不确定 或许是他们集会的地方？
I'm not sure, but maybe they gathered here?
你能想象吗 身处这个地方
Can you imagine being right here,
那么久以前 就在这个地方？
right in this very spot back then?
他们讲述的那些故事？
The stories that they told?
这里很久以前肯定发生过很多事
So much history I'm sure happened right here.
我们无处可逃了
They've got us cornered.
-好 我们必须往上爬 走 -什么？
-Okay. We've got to go up. Come on. -What?
你看到我穿的什么吗？
Have you seen what I'm wearing?
我穿着带闪片的紧身衣
I'm in a glitter straitjacket.
除了往上爬没有别的出路 来吧 我们走
There's nowhere to go but up. Come on. Let's go.
我不该干这个 我太老了
I should not be doing this. I'm too old for this.
不 你不老 你很美
No, you're not. You're beautiful.
我没说我不美 我是说我过了这么干的年纪
I didn't say I'm not beautiful. I said I'm too old to be doing this.
我不能思考的时候 我的技能也不能思考
My skill is sitting and thinking and eating
于是就干坐着吃东西
when I can't think.
你的鞋的确是不太适合登山
Yeah, you definitely could be wearing better shoes for this.
这鞋是你带来的
You brought me these shoes.
我不行了 爬不动了
I can't go any further. I can't go any further.
我感觉不太舒服
I'm not doing so great here.
你可以的 加油
You got it. Come on.
我知道你觉得抓紧了不要动更安全
I know you think that you're safer holding on,
但你必须继续爬
but you have to keep going.
-我不行 我做不到 -好吗？
-I can't. I can't, I can't. -Okay?
-你闻到没？ -闻到什么？
-Do you smell that? -Smell what?
-有一股味道 -是猛兽吗？什么味道？
-I smell something. -Is it a predator? What is it?
-有火烧下来了？ -你得深吸气好好闻
-A downward cascading fire? -You got to smell deeper.
我什么都闻不到
I don't smell anything!
深吸一口气
Take a big, deep breath.
好
All right.
-好样的 -好
-Good job. -Okay.
-处理得很巧妙 谢了 -确实很巧妙
-That was manipulative. Thank you. -Yeah, it was.
好 我来帮你一把 好吗？
Here we go. I'm gonna help you out a little bit, all right?
-一 二 三…用力 -你干什么呢？
-One, two, three… Here we go! -What are you doing?
-快出来 -用力
-Get out of there. -Come on.
-不 别收紧 -那是我的敏感部位
-No, no, don't flex. -That's my hoo-hoo.
就骑在头上 手不要停 骑在头上
Just ride the head. Keep the hands moving and ride the head.
-天啊 -你做得很好
-Oh, God. -You're doing great.
抱歉发型有点扎人 加把劲
Sorry about the scratchy haircut. Come on.
苦后更甜
Dulcius ex asperis.
你说什么？
What was that?
没什么
Oh, nothing.
就是以前我和约翰
It was just something that John and I would say
在完成一件大工作
after we finished something big, like a…
比如考古挖掘或者手稿之后 会说的一句话
like an archaeological dig or a manuscript.
是拉丁语 意思是“苦后更甜”
It's Latin. It means "sweeter after difficulty."
拉丁语的…
What's…
“洛蕾塔真厉害”怎么说？
What's Latin for "Loretta's a badass"?
我是很厉害 我爬上了一座山
I am a badass. I climbed a mountain.
天啊 要是贝丝能看到我们这样就好了
Oh, my God. I wish Beth could've seen us do this.
-天啊 贝丝 -别担心贝丝
-Oh, God. Beth. -Don't worry about Beth.
她可能已经发动全体海军在找我们了
She's probably got the whole navy after us right now.
我知道你觉得你必须亲自去找
I get that you think you have to go to
那座岛上的相关机构
the island authorities yourself,
尽管放心吧
but don't worry,
我会让洛蕾塔的 社交网络超级活跃
I'm keeping Loretta's socials super active.
刚在推特上发了：“我这是被绑架了吗？
Just tweeted, "Did I just get kidnapped?
主题标签 真倒霉
#FML,
@肖恩门德斯 主题标签 肖恩门德斯”
@ShawnMendes, #ShawnMendes."
你是一个人出行？
And you're traveling alone?
是的 我一个人 我单身
Yes, I'm traveling alone. I'm single.
那或许行得通
Then this might work.
-好 快告诉我 -你可以先去纽约
-Okay! Talk to me. -You'll hit New York.
从那里飞往几内亚
From there, you'll fly to Guinea,
然后在那里搭一架小破鸟
where you can pick up a puddle jumper.
一架什么？
A what?
-小型飞机 -对 没有腿部空间
-Small plane. -Yeah, no leg room.
没关系 可以
That's fine. I'll take it.
-或者你可以直接回来 -谢谢
-Or you could just come home. -Thank you.
我们需要更加易燃的东西 这里太潮湿了
We need something more flammable. Everything is just so wet.
这里面…你包里有什么？
What's in here? What's in your bag?
-东西真不少 好 -你在干什么？
-Oh, a lot. Okay. -What are you doing?
好 面膜
Okay. Face masks.
对 那是礼品篮里送的
Yeah, that was like a gift-basket thing.
你带了个香薰蜡烛到丛林里来？
You brought a scented candle into the jungle?
那是我妈给我的
My mom gave me that.
是母亲节的奇怪礼物
It was like a weird gift for Mother's Day.
母亲节你妈妈送你礼物？
Your mom gives you gifts for Mother's Day?
桉树迷迭香精油
Eucalyptus rosemary oil.
真好闻
That smells good.
好吧
Oh, okay. All right.
太好了
Yes!
我生了火
Yes, I made fire!
-真厉害 你得… -这火真漂亮
-That's pretty impressive. You have to-- -It is a beautiful fire.
谁想得到呢？
Who would have thought?
这就把上衣脱了？
Oh, you're just taking your shirt off?
看上去挺不舒服的
That looks really uncomfortable.
你背上还好吧？
Are you okay? The back?
对 所以我才不喜欢碰水
Yeah. That is why I don't do water.
-好吧 -身上会变得像少年长痘的脸一样
-Okay. -My body becomes an eighth-grader's face.
你有涂的东西吗 软膏之类的？
Do you have anything for it? Like some ointment or something?
有 原本是有的
Yeah, I do. Well, I did.
装在一个小瓶子里
It was in a little, tiny little bottle.
是这瓶 对不起啊
It was this. I'm sorry.
真对不起
Oh, God, I'm sorry.
没关系
It's okay.
-等等 好 快过来 -做什么？
-Hold on. Yes. Come here. Come here. -What?
-过来 坐下 -我看看
-Come here. Sit down. -Let me see.
-快坐下 -这里？
-Just sit down. -Right here?
对
Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
不 你不必碰的 没关系
No, you don't have to touch it. It's okay. It's fine.
我连你身上充血的袋子都碰了 所以…
I touched your engorged sacks, so…
-那些蚂蟥 -好吧
-The leeches. -Okay.
好 可能有点凉
Okay, this might be a little bit cold.
-抱歉 -哇
-Sorry. -Oh, yeah.
抱歉
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
或许达什就该是这种死法
Maybe this is how Dash should die.
严重的湿疹发作 多性感
Horrible eczema outbreak. That's so sexy.
我能写好
I could make it work.
是吗？
Yeah?
那好
All right, then.
你会怎么写？
How would you write this?
好
Okay.
“在温暖芳香的篝火边…”
"Warmed by the fragrant fire…"
开头就这么带感
Starting strong.
“洛芙摩尔的双手…
"Lovemore's hands explored the…
探索着达什身体的轮廓
the contoured scenery
勾勒出醉人的风景
of Dash's body.
熟悉的起伏
Familiar terrain made
随着一道道猩红的凸起
new and exciting with every…
有了令人心跳加速的新鲜感”
with every scarlet rim."
她没有觉得…
And that didn't…
倒胃口吗？
didn't turn her off?
没有
No.
“因为洛芙摩尔能够听到
"Because with every cardinal ridge,
每座红色的山脊都在呢哝细语
Lovemore discovered another letter in the language
说着只有他们的身体才懂的语言”
that only their bodies spoke."
那他们的身体在说什么？
And what were their bodies saying?
“占有我…
"Take me…
占有我
take me,
占有我”
take me."
你觉得怎么样？
How's that?
挺好的
It was good.
-我是说你背上感觉怎么样了？ -挺好
-Your back. I mean, how is your back? -Good.
-好 你确定吗？ -对
-Okay. You sure? -Yeah.
-我说的也是我的背 还有这里 -好
-I also meant my back. Right there, yeah. -Okay.
生活必需品
Supplies.
我有点冷 要不我等会儿就进去躺下
Okay, I'm chilly. I think I'm gonna probably turn in in a little bit.
-行 -你没事吧？
-Okay. -You good?
没事 我很火…好 我很好
Yeah, I'm fire-- fine. I'm fine.
我不“火” 我待在火边很好
I'm not "fire." I'm fine by the fire.
好吧
Okay. All right.
随便你啦 但如果你冷的话
It's up to you, but if you're cold,
我们俩大概都能挤进来 如果你愿意的话
maybe we could probably both fit in here, if you wanted to.
我们俩一起？
Both of us?
-如果你愿意的话 我只是… -好 不 听上去…
-Only if you want to. I mean, it's just-- -Yeah, no, that sounds…
好 你准备怎么…
Okay. How do you…
你可以先进去 然后我再想办法
You can go first, then I'll figure it out.
不 你先进 绝对应该女士优先
No, no, you go. It's definitely a "ladies first" type of situation.
-把手保持在袋子外面 -我就是这么打算的
-Keep hands out of the bag at all times. -That's what I was gonna do.
-背靠背 -手在外 背靠背
-Butt to butt. -Hands out and butt to butt.
-好 我怎么做？ -直接进来 先坐下
-Yeah. What do I do? -Just get in. Go ahead and sit.
我先坐？好 坐下了
I sit first? Okay. I'm in.
你太重了 会把袋子坐个底朝天的
You're too heavy. You're gonna flip this thing like a cruise ship.
你自己小心 等等 我还没进来
You watch yourself. Hold on. I'm not in.
怎么还要用到核心肌群呢？
Why is this engaging my core so much?
你往那边蹭蹭行吗？
How 'bout you shimmy?
-我没法呼吸 喘不过气了 -你可以吗？
-I can't breathe. I'm not breathing. -Are you good?
我的脸
My face.
好
Yeah. Okay.
手拿出来 背对背
Hands are out. Butt to butt.
好
Okay.
行啊
Well!
来
Come on.
来啊 大声点
Come on! Let's hear it!
我们来为洛蕾塔鼓掌
Let's give a nice round of applause to Loretta!
她真有本事
She earned it.
一个手无缚鸡之力的大龄宅女
A geriatric shut-in left you
让你们在丛林里干瞪眼
holding your dicks in the jungle.
好样的 洛蕾塔
Good job, Loretta.
拜托 老大 搞出人命了
Boss, come on. People are dying now.
难道你不觉得这样有点过了吗？
Don't you think that maybe this has all gone too far?
真的值得吗？
Is it really worth it?
我只差一点就要实现世人无法企及的梦想
I am on the cusp of attaining the unattainable.
一件美轮美奂的宝物 世上任何一个国家
Something singular, something no nation,
任何一位君王
no emperor,
或者任何一个马屁精兄弟都没有的东西
no brownnosing brothers ever have.
传说中的火焰皇冠
The legendary Crown of Fire.
所以是啊
So, yes.
我觉得这完全值得
Yes, I would definitely say it's worth it.
劳驾
Excuse me!
劳驾 先生 我得去搭转机的航班
Excuse me, sir. I need to get to my next connecting flight.
没有航班
No flight.
飞行员病了 明天再来
The pilot is sick. Come tomorrow.
不 先生 我不能明天再来 我今天就得飞
No, no, sir. I cannot come tomorrow. I need to do this today.
我今晚就得赶到洪迪达岛
I need to get to the island Isla Hundida tonight.
性命攸关哪
Lives are at stake.
明天再来
Come tomorrow.
-打扰了 女士 -什么事？
-Excuse me, miss? -Yes?
我刚才无意中听到你说你喜欢吃牛排大餐
I couldn't help but overhear you say that you like steak.
好 你听了可能会不相信
Okay, this is a little bit crazy,
但我也喜欢牛排大餐
but I also like steak.
-什么？ -我也喜欢牛排大餐
-What? -I also like steak.
你想不想…怎么说呢…
Would you like to, maybe, I don't know…
-或许我们可以… -不 “性命攸关”
-Maybe there's a… -No. "Lives are at stake."
我今晚就得赶到岛上去
I need to go to the island tonight.
对
Yes.
-那就更重要了 -相当重要
-Even more serious. -Extremely.
我想我能够帮上忙
Well, I believe that I may be able to assist you.
我有一架货运飞机
I have a cargo plane.
或许等我送完货 我们可以顺道去你的小岛
Maybe after I make my delivery, we could swing by your island.
我问你一个问题 你最好老实回答
I'm gonna ask you something, and you better tell me the truth.
你以前杀过人吗？
Have you ever murdered anyone before?
没有
No!
我不能说我完全相信 但你给我听好了
I don't know if I really buy it, but let me tell you something.
如果你敢动杀我的念头
If you ever think about murdering me,
我绝对会先杀了你
I promise, I will murder you first.
不客气
My pleasure.
你真是个怪人 我们走吧
You are weird. Let's go.
“卡拉曼国王和他的珍宝安息在无尽的
"King Kalaman and his treasure laid to rest in the well
眼泪之井中”
of endless tears."
什么东西？
What is that?
没什么东西 不是…
Oh, it's a thing. I mean, it's not…
不是你以为的东西
You know, it's not what you think it is.
所以说这不是 费尔法克斯那块
So it's not Fairfax's fragment
古老的羊皮纸残片？
of an ancient parchment?
好吧 就是你以为的东西
Okay. It's what you think it is.
洛蕾塔 你怎么就犯糊涂了呢
Loretta, I thought you were smarter than that.
这下费尔法克斯绝对会穷追不舍
Fairfax is never gonna stop hunting us now.
你是怎么想的？
What were you thinking?
那座火山一旦喷发 陵墓就会被掩埋
We have a volcano that could bury the tomb
我们就来不及赶过去看一眼
before we get to it, before we see it,
来不及保存关于它的记忆
before we preserve its memory.
-这是… -不好意思 我们是要去找陵墓吗？
-This is-- -I'm sorry. Is that what we're doing?
我怎么不知道？你打算什么时候告诉我？
'Cause no one told me. When were you gonna tell me?
我为什么要告诉你？
Why would I tell you?
我们俩是一条船上的 我来这里是为了救你
We're in this together. I came here to rescue you.
你知道你不是达什吧？
You know you're not Dash, right?
你不会骑着白马英雄救美
You don't ride in on a white horse to rescue people.
你只会往身上喷古铜粉
You… spray yourself with bronzer
站在鼓风机前面摆造型
and you stand in front of wind machines,
这对你而言很好
which is great for you.
你怎么知道我其实是怎样的？
How would you have any idea what I'm actually like?
我了解你 你这人很容易读 艾伦
I know you. You're a pretty open book, Alan.
-那好 我是怎样的？ -真的吗？
-Okay, then who am I? -Really?
对啊
Yeah.
行啊
Okay.
你是全校的校草 因为长得帅
You were a homecoming king
轻轻松松地来到了洛杉矶
and you coasted on your good looks to LA,
可随后你意识到
but then realized that
在一个偏僻的无名小镇里长得最帅
being the most handsome kid in the middle of nowhere
并不意味着你会出人头地
doesn't mean you're going to be a star.
直到有一天 一个女人因为没法出版
Until one day, when a woman who couldn't publish her book
她写的关于大西洋西班牙殖民主义的书
on Spanish colonization in the Atlantic
转而决定写一本言情小说
decided to write a romance novel,
并且碰巧选了你当封面模特
chose you at random to be on the cover.
你们俩都交了好运 小说大卖
Lucky for you and her, the novels were a smashing success.
于是她继续写低俗小说 你继续摆造型
She kept writing her schlock, you kept posing,
我们俩都没有成为自己想成为的人
you know, neither one of us becoming who we'd hoped we would be.
然后有一天 我们都死在了热带丛林里
And then one day, we both die in the jungle
就在我很多年前写过的
on one of those Atlantic islands I wrote
大西洋中的一座小岛上
about all those years ago.
对吧？
Right?
是萨拉索塔
It was Sarasota, by the way.
不是无名小镇
It's not nowhere.
我在那里长大 还有我妈和两个姐姐
I grew up there with my mom and two sisters.
没错
And yeah.
我开始当模特是因为我想离开那里
I started modeling 'cause I wanted to get away.
我只能想到这一份工作
It was the only job that I could think of
能够让我去那些
that could take me to all of the places
我一直梦想能去的地方
that I always dreamed of going.
后来终于到了洛杉矶
Then finally to Los Angeles,
我当了你言情小说的封面模特
where I posed on the cover of your romance novel.
我尴尬得要死 就怕朋友们看到了
I was so embarrassed that one of my friends might've seen me
我在小说封面上戴着假发的样子
in that wig on the cover of your book
所以好几个月不敢跟他们说话
that I avoided talking to them for months.
后来有一天
And then one day,
我走在回家的路上
I'm walking home,
听见一位女士喊：“达什！”
and I hear this lady yell, "Dash!"
她跑到我面前 特别开心
She runs up, and she is so happy.
于是我就想：“能让别人这么开心
Then I thought, "How could I be this embarrassed
我怎么能觉得尴尬呢？”
about something that makes people this happy?"
洛蕾塔 你想怎样都行
Loretta, you can do whatever you want.
如果你不想写书了 那就不要写
If you don't want to write anymore, don't write.
但不要贬低你的读者
But don't minimize the people that love your work
说那是低俗小说
by calling it schlock.
这对他们不公平
That's not fair to them.
你知道什么事很讽刺吗？
You know what's ironic?
我原以为你是
I thought you of all people would know
最不会以貌取人的
not to judge a book by its cover.
以封面取人
Judge a book by its cover model.
艾伦？
Alan?
艾伦
Alan.
他们有两个人
There's two of them.
-洛蕾塔 我在这里 -艾伦
-Loretta! I'm over here! -Alan!
艾伦 摩托车还有枪
Alan! Motorcycles and guns, motorcycles and guns!
这边！
Come this way!
别开枪了！
Stop shooting!
-把羊皮纸给他们 -不行
-Just give 'em the parchment! -I can't.
行的 你就喊一声“给你” 然后扔过去
Yes, you can, actually. You just say, "Here," and throw it at 'em.
对 然后他们肯定会乖乖放过我们
Right. And then I'm sure they'll happily let us go.
-好 快蹲下 -他们怎么总能找到我们？
-Okay, keep down. -How do they keep finding us?
你这身衣服能把人闪瞎
You're basically a walking disco ball.
我们得想个办法
We need to come up with a plan.
我有个主意
I have an idea.
我们挖个洞 然后假装喊
We're gonna dig a hole, throw our voices.
“我们在这里” 你会学鸟叫吗？
"We're over here." Can you sound like a bird?
-不 我有个主意 -艾伦 拜托 我在想办法呢
-No, I have a plan. -Alan, please, I'm thinking.
-我知道 但我有个办法 -就让我想一想…
-I know, but I have a plan. -Please, just let me think about…
等等 他们在朝你开枪
Wait a minute. They're shooting at you.
对 所以我们才要躲起来
Yeah, that's why we're hiding.
不 他们只朝你开枪
No. They're shooting only at you.
他们不打我 因为我的脑袋才有价值
They won't shoot me. It's my brain that's valuable.
你也不听听你这话说的…
I don't think you actually hear the things you say sometimes.
-或许我能掩护你 -你不能掩护我
-Maybe I can shield you. -You are not shielding me.
-该我掩护你 -为什么 因为我是女人？
-I should be shielding you. -Why? Because I'm a woman?
这完全就是性别歧视
That's supremely sexist.
用女性当挡箭牌
I don't think using women as human shields
应该和格洛丽亚斯恩菲德主张的
is exactly the change that Gloria Seinfeld
女权主义思想不符吧？
had in mind, do you?
格洛丽亚斯泰纳姆？
Gloria Steinem?
无所谓 她也是 行
Whatever. Her too. You know what? Fine.
请用男性说教的口吻 解释下什么是性别歧视
Please mansplain sexism to me right now.
我的天啊 我是个女人
Oh, my God. I am a woman.
我不会用男性说教的口吻讲话
I can't mansplain anything.
我是个女权主义者
I'm a feminist,
我觉得男人能做到的事 女人也能做到
and I think a woman can do anything a man can do.
我们得待在这里 等他们找累了
We just need to stay here until they get tired.
-我有个想法 我能说说我的办法吗？ -艾伦
-I have an idea. Can I tell you my plan? -Alan!
这不是你扒扒上衣就能解决的事
This is not a situation you can get out of by ripping your shirt off.
不是扒我的
Not my shirt.
三
Three!
好！
Yes!
这和我设想的不一样
That was different than I had in my head.
我只是想拦住他们
I just wanted us to stop them.
会不会是因为有风才这样的？
Could it have been the wind that made it do that?
不 我觉得是我们 是我们干的
No, I think it was us. I think… we did it.
我们拦了一个人 对吧？但那是…
We did the one guy, right? But that was, like…
我们只是想让他停下
We just wanted him to stop.
但另外那个人完全可以躲开的
But the other guy could've moved, really.
所以要怪他自己
So, that one was on him.
就算没有我们 这种事还是会发生
Even if we weren't here, that could've happened.
你停在悬崖边做什么？
Why are you gonna stop next to a cliff?
他们戴了头盔 所以他们可能…
They were wearing helmets, so maybe they're…
但他们身上其他部位没有戴头盔
But the rest of their body didn't have a helmet.
所以可能就只有脑袋
So there'd just be a head.
他们这是鲁莽驾驶 对吧？
They were driving recklessly, right?
骑车时不能有坏心眼
Don't be mean on a bike.
骑车时不能做坏事
Don't do mean stuff on a bike.
说不定他们没事
I mean, perhaps they're fine.
或许有事 但没关系
Yeah, probably not. But that's okay.
没关系 世事难料嘛 我们走吧
That's all right. You know, things happen. Let's go.
-你要再缝起来还是怎的？ -这是租的
-You gonna put it back together? -It's on loan.
-瞧瞧我 -好啊
-Look at me. -Okay.
我还能怎样？
What more can I do, you know?
你已经做了很多 贝丝
You've done so much already, Beth.
我可怜可亲的奶奶 视力不行了
My poor, sweet, little Nana has lost her sight.
新书发布会搞砸了
The book release is a complete disaster,
我把宝全押在了上面
which I've leveraged everything on,
所以我可能已经百分百地破产了
so I'm probably, most definitely broke right now.
而最重要的是 我弄丢了一名作者
And most importantly, I've lost a writer.
谁会这样？谁会弄丢作者？
Who does that? Who loses a writer?
好吧 贝丝 你让我想起了 我最好的朋友兰迪
Okay, Beth, you remind me of my best friend, Randy.
总是为其他人操心
Always looking out for other people,
从来不知道照顾自己
never taking care of herself.
对吧 兰迪？
Isn't that right, Randy?
这孩子 它就像是我的治疗师
She's like my therapist, this one over here.
LOL “哈哈大笑”
LOL. "Laughing Out Loud."
你处理完朋友的事之后
After you take care of your friend,
我们俩去海滩怎么样？
how about we go to a beach?
-什么？ -我要去夏威夷取货
-What? -Look, I have a pickup in Hawaii.
不用带上它
She doesn't have to come.
好吧 你可以一起来
Okay! Okay, you can come!
它太有意思了
She's hilarious.
我问你一个问题
Let me ask you something.
我们都坐在这里唠嗑 谁在开飞机？
We're all sitting here chitchatting, but who's flying the plane?
-自动驾驶 -什么？
-Autopilot. -What?
大哥 快去驾驶舱 好好开飞机
Sir, go to the cockpit, fly the plane.
好吧
Okay.
我去降落
I'm going to go land the plane.
好
Okay.
不 把羊带走 麻烦你把羊带走
No, no, no. Take the goat. Please, take the goat.
现在是它的休息时间 祝你飞行愉快
She's on break. Enjoy the flight!
嗨
Hi.
来了个英国人 就把她绑架了
This English dude came in and basically kidnapped her.
嗨 我是贝丝 请留言
Hey, it's Beth. Please leave a message,
我会尽快回复
and I'll get right back to you.
嗨 贝丝
Hi, Beth.
是我
It's me.
我还活着
I'm alive!
是这样的…
Listen…
我很抱歉我把签书会搞砸了
I'm sorry that I blew up the book tour.
我就是很害怕
I was just afraid
而且很自私
and selfish.
艾伦来了 我回头再打给你
Here comes Alan. I'll call you back.
警方在找费尔法克斯
So, police are searching for Fairfax,
我们待在这里时 他们会保护我们
and they're gonna provide us protection while we're here.
他们说没说我们得在这里待多久？
Did they say how long we'd be here?
他们会尽量在今晚 帮我们安排一架小型飞机
They're gonna try to get us on a puddle jumper later this evening.
但他们说那家小旅馆不错 在走之前
But they said in the meantime, the inn is really nice,
我们可以去清洗一下 换身衣服
and we can get cleaned up and maybe a change of clothes.
好的
Okay.
那好
Okay. Yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
来啊
Come on.
跟你老公跳个舞
Dance with your husband.
-不 -他不是我老公
-No, no, no. -He's not my husband.
-没事的 -跟他跳个舞
-It's okay. -Dance with him.
不 她不想跳 她穿的鞋不适合跳舞
No, no. She doesn't want to. She doesn't have the right shoes.
其实 这双鞋唯一适合的就是跳舞
Actually, it's the only thing these shoes are right for.
你不必勉强的
You don't have to do this.
没关系
It's okay. It's okay.
是吗？
Yeah?
也不知道她唱的是什么意思
I wonder what she's saying.
是个民间传说
It's folklore.
是首情歌 讲的是一个女子
Love song about a woman
她的爱人死了 但她不想离开爱人身边
whose lover died, and she didn't want to leave his side.
于是她就躺在那里 不肯起来
So she laid down and refused to get up.
一定很可怕
Must be scary.
两人一起计划的未来
Having to face your future
却只剩下一个人独自面对
without the person that you planned it with.
她说什么？
What was that?
不好意思 你刚唱的那句歌词
Excuse me. The last line that you sang.
“谁会为我哭泣？”
¿Quién llorará junto a mí?
“小岛会在无尽的眼泪之井中为我哭泣”
"The island will weep for me in the well of endless tears."
“无尽的眼泪之井”是什么？
What is that, the well of endless tears?
是个真实存在的地方还是…
Is that a real place, or…
天坑的地方
Sinkhole place.
谢谢你 谢谢
Thank you. Gracias, gracias.
-来 快来 -怎么了？
-Come here, come here. -What is it?
羊皮纸上说
Hey, on the parchment, it said,
“卡拉曼国王和他的珍宝
"King Kalaman and his treasure
安息在无尽的眼泪之井中”
laid to rest in the well of endless tears."
我原以为是个比喻
I thought maybe it was a metaphor.
其实不是
It's not.
无尽的眼泪之井是个地名
The Well of Endless Tears is a place.
是一个天坑
It's a sinkhole.
地图上就有一个天坑
There's a sinkhole on the map.
我想陵墓就在那里
I think the tomb is there.
-这比你书里写的精彩多了 -什么？
-This is so much better than your books. -What?
不 我没有冒犯你的意思
There's like-- No, I don't mean any offense.
-我开玩笑的 -是一样精彩
-I'm kidding. I'm kidding. -It's, like, equal.
-我开玩笑的 -瞧瞧你 你想去那里
-I'm kidding. I'm kidding. -Look at you. You want to go there.
-什么？我没有 -我看得出来 你就是想去
-What? No. -I can see. Yes, you do.
那该有多荒唐啊 我只是…
That would be insane. That would be insane. I just…
只是我们已经离得这么近了 但是我们不能…
It's just that we're so close to it, but, you know, we can't--
不
No.
这是你的故事 你想怎么写？
This is your story. How do you want to write it?
我想知道那里是存在的
I'd like to know that it's there,
这一切是有意义的
that all this meant something.
好 那我们去吧
Okay. Then let's go.
我们多待一天 等天一亮
We'll stay one more day. As soon as the sun's up,
我们就去找无尽的眼泪之井
we're gonna go find the Well of Endless Tears.
但万一找不到呢？
But what if it's nothing?
那又怎样？至少我们努力过了
So what? Then we say we tried.
那费尔法克斯怎么办？
And Fairfax?
警察在找费尔法克斯 不用担心
The cops are after Fairfax. Don't worry about him.
-多荒唐啊 -对 但看看你
-This is crazy. -Yeah, but look at you.
怎么了？
What?
这是我第一次见到你毫无畏惧的样子
It's the very first time I've ever seen you totally unafraid.
而且充满了活力
And alive.
我去告诉他们计划有变 请他们帮忙找辆车
I'm gonna go tell them our plans have changed and find us a ride.
你去哪里？
Where are you going?
你应该见过我朋友了
I see you met my friend here.
他告诉我 你打算跳上飞机
He told me you were just about to jump on a plane,
不辞而别
without so much as saying goodbye.
我就说：“不可能 我的洛蕾塔不会的
I said, "No way. Not my Loretta.
毕竟她是唯一一个能带我去陵墓的人”
Not when she's the only one who can lead me to the tomb."
别那么用力掐我了
Stop squeezing so hard.
你给我松手
Get your hands off of me!
放开我
Let go!
我需要一辆车 汽车 谁有汽车？
I need a car. A car, an auto. Does anybody have an auto?
不
No, no. No.
我需要辆车 我拿手表跟你换
I need an auto. I'll trade you my watch.
这表很贵的
It's a really expensive watch.
你有车吗？ 这是块宝格丽 在黑暗中会发光的
Do you have a car? It's a Bulgari. This thing glows in the dark.
-还有防水功能 -我有辆摩托车
-It's waterproof. -I have motorcycle.
很酷吧？
Cool, isn't it?
我总觉得
I always thought,
私人坦克里 也装个迷你吧有何不可？
why can't your personal tank also have a minibar?
喝杯酒
Have a drink.
-注意点行吗？ -对了
-Do you mind? -Yes.
恐怕他对你有点意见
He has a bit of a grudge against you, I'm afraid.
好像和他的朋友骑摩托出意外有关？
Something about a motorbike accident his friends had?
你为什么要这么做？
Why are you doing this?
我想要一件没人拥有的东西
I want something nobody else has.
当我爸把他的…
When my father gifted--
好的
As I was saying,
当我爸把他的企业帝国送给我弟时…
when my father gifted his empire to my baby brother--
什么人啊？
Who is that?
是个骑着机车的男芭比吗？
Is that a Ken doll on a moped?
我好像在哪里见过他
I know him from somewhere.
我觉得不会
Oh, I doubt that.
因为那个人是一名训练有素的格斗专家
Because what you are looking at is a highly trained combat specialist,
他久经沙场 去过阿富汗 伊拉克
forged in the furnaces of Afghanistan, Iraq,
科威特 萨拉索塔…
Kuwait, Sarasota…
皮肤特别好 不长湿疹
Incredible skin. No eczema problems.
救不到我 他决不会罢休
And he will not stop until I am safe!
所以你最好乖乖停下这辆太空坦克
So you pull this space tank over,
除非你想像他的朋友一样一命呜呼
unless you would like to perish like his friends did.
就是他让他们一命呜呼的
And he is responsible for their perishment.
这可能并不是他的本意
He might not have meant to,
但是他们…还是呜呼了 所以…
but they… perished, so…
这人到底是谁？我以前在哪见过他
Okay, who is this? I have seen him somewhere before.
不是吧 他是你的封面模特 对吧？
No, no, no. That's your cover model, isn't it?
对 我就说在哪见过
Yes. I knew I knew him from somewhere.
上去
Get up there.
干掉他 要有点创意
And kill him creatively.
我喜欢看肌肉型男栽跟头
I love watching hunks fail.
我现在喝一杯行吗？
I guess I will have that drink.
该死
Oh, shit.
我倒满行吗？
Is it okay if I just top 'er off?
行 但是…天啊 你会用杯子吗？
Yeah, that's fine, but-- Oh, my God, have you used a glass before?
对不起
Sorry.
杰克教官会怎么做？
What would Jack Trainer do?
这里真热 还有谁觉得这里很热？
It's hot in here. Anyone else feeling how hot it is?
你是在扮性感吗？看着好奇怪 请你打住
Are you trying to be sexy? This is very weird. Please, stop.
我可以让你的世界燃烧起来
I could set your world on fire.
睡吧！睡！给我睡！
Go to sleep! Go to sleep! Go to sleep! Sleep!
暂停
Time-out.
继续
Time-in!
不！别打到她 她还有用！
No! Don't shoot her! I need her!
天啊
Jesus!
脚挪开！给我挪开！
Move your foot! Move your foot!
去睡吧 王八蛋
Go to sleep, asshole.
出去 看着点！
Get out there! Look!
这个块头更大
A bigger guy?
不
Oh, no.
什么？
What?
让开
Move it!
不
No, no, no. No, no, no.
喂 进来
Hey! Get in.
他还是我？
Him or me?
洛蕾塔 这可不是你那种
This is not one of your cheap,
粗俗乏味的女性意淫小说
vapid lady-fantasy books, Loretta.
这是现实生活
This is real life.
我们会杀了他
And we will kill him.
告诉我们 陵墓在哪里
Tell us where the tomb is.
嗨 不知道哪位是管事的 请你派人去这个地方
Hi. So, whoever's in charge, I need you to send officials to go here.
这里
Here.
我们下班了
We are closed.
你们下班了？
You're closed?
知道吗 我盼着能睡个午觉 已经盼了一年半了
You know I've been trying to take a nap for a year and a half?
一年半哪
A year and a half.
我玩命地工作
I have been burning the candle at both ends,
起早贪黑
the midnight oil,
我朋友被绑架前 我早就这样了
since way before my friend got kidnapped.
我唯一想要的
And all I want to do
就是翘起双腿放松一下
is kick my feet back
喝杯小酒 虽然我可能太累了喝不下
and drink some wine that I'm probably too tired to drink.
而且我想做趟按摩
And I want a massage.
我想有人帮我按摩下肩膀和双脚
I want someone to massage my shoulders and my feet,
而且要同时进行
and I want it at the same time.
我不在乎这在逻辑上是否可行
And I don't care if logistically that doesn't make sense.
因为我非常努力地工作
Because I have worked hard.
我知道你们也是一样地努力
The same way that I know that you have.
所以我不得不请求你们
So I hate to ask you
再稍微晚两分钟下班
to leave this place open a few more minutes,
因为否则的话
because if we don't,
我的一位非常亲密的朋友 还有她的封面模特
a very close friend of mine and her cover model
就要小命不保
are going to die.
进不去 老大
No good way in, boss!
走山洞呢？
What about the caves?
太危险了
That's too dangerous!
我们会非常小心的
Well, we'll be very careful then.
快点啊
Well, come on!
这边
This way.
我有个不进诡异山洞的原则
I have a rule about not going into super creepy caves.
-朱利安？ -他叫朱利安？
-Julian? -His name is Julian?
他看上去更像“巴克”或者“布鲁斯”
He seems more like a Buck or a Bruce.
你来带路
Lead the way.
走啊 别害怕
Go on. Don't be scared.
当心脚下
Watch your step there.
-布鲁斯 朱利安 -朱利安 不！
-Bruce! Julian! -Julian. Oh, no!
好吧
Well…
不要让他的死白费
Let's not have his death be in vain.
-继续前进 -什么叫继续前进？
-Onward and upward. -What do you mean onward?
我们总不能下去找他吧？
We're not gonna go and get him now, are we?
天啊
Oh, man.
-什么都没有 -好吧
-It's nothing. -Okay.
我们回船上去吧
Yeah, let's just go back to the boat.
结束了 没必要再搞出人命
This is over. Nobody else has to die.
不 这里有风
No, no, no. It's a breeze.
这里有条隧道 可能就通往陵墓
There's a tunnel. This could lead to the tomb.
-这里过不去人 -是你自己过不去
-That's not person-sized. -Speak for yourself.
行了 这跟小孩子的滑梯差不多
Come on. It's practically a kiddie slide.
-更像是岩石的括约肌 -或者巨怪的肛门
-More like a rock sphincter. -Or a troll anus.
你就得钻进这个肛门…洞…隧道
Well, you are going through the anus-- the hole-- the tunnel!
-为什么是她？ -你就是我们的预警系统
-Why her? -You are our canary in the coal mine.
不 不可能 我做不到
No, that's impossible. I can't.
你过去了就告诉我们一声
Please let us know if you get through.
如果听不到你的信号 他就没命了
If we don't hear from you, Fabio's got to die.
等等 我是落难少女？
Wait, I'm the damsel in distress?
没事 我可以的
It's okay. I'm fine.
不行 对不起 我做不到
I can't. I'm so sorry. I can't.
-嘿 -什么？
-Hey. -What?
你闻到了吗？
You smell that?
你是说积累了几百年的蝙蝠屎吗？
You mean centuries worth of bat feces?
我当然闻到了
Yes, I definitely smell that.
我要你深吸一口气
You gotta take a big breath for me.
就是这样
There you go.
你可以的 洛蕾塔
You can do it, Loretta.
我想我看到出口了
I think I see a way out.
老天爷啊
Cheese and rice!
我过来了
I made it!
看吧？安全得很
See? Totally safe.
走吧 轮到你了
Go on. Your turn.
我要过来了 马上就到 好吗？
I'm coming through! Be right there, okay?
他们为什么建在这里？
Why would they build this here?
如果别人看不到的话
But how is anyone supposed to worship
还怎么来敬奉祭拜？
or remember you if they can't even see it?
那不是目的
They aren't.
这里不是卡拉曼权力的丰碑
This isn't a monument to Kalaman's power.
而是一个伤心女人藏身的地方
It's a hiding place for a grieving woman.
塔哈来这里陪伴她死去的恋人
Taha came here to be with her fallen lover.
她只想一个人待着
She just wanted to be alone.
塔哈不欢迎我们
Taha doesn't want us here.
天啊 住嘴 拉菲
God, shut up, Rafi.
只是火山而已
It's just the volcano.
过来
Come on.
我们得继续前进
We have to keep going.
好了 快点过来 两位壮汉
All right. Let's go, Muscles.
把这个打开
Open it up.
-不要打扰他们 -皇冠肯定就在她头上
-Don't disturb them. -She will be wearing the headdress.
快点 我们大老远找来 可不是为了来祭拜
Come on. We didn't come all this way just to pay our respects.
我不能…
I can't…
对不起 外婆
I'm sorry, abuela.
这是什么？
What is that?
是…贝壳？
Are those… seashells?
皇冠是贝壳做的？
The crown is made of seashells?
珍宝在哪里？
Where's the treasure?
在她的怀里
She's holding him.
你是说这个死人？
You mean the dead guy?
看
Look.
这是他们的爱情故事
It's their courtship.
卡拉曼在这座岛上寻找某样东西
Kalaman is searching the island for something.
罕见的红色贝壳
Rare red seashells.
为了证明他的爱
To prove his love,
他每天送她一个贝壳 持续了一年
he gave her one shell every day for a year
然后用这些贝壳做了一顶皇冠
and made them into a crown,
颜色鲜红 就像他们的爱情之火
bright red like the flame of their love,
直到有一天 她终于答应成为他的妻子
until the day came where she accepted his proposal.
这从来就和珠宝无关
It was never about jewels.
卡拉曼和塔哈的财富并不是物质财富
Kalaman and Taha's riches weren't material.
而是他们的爱情
It was their love.
这就是它的意义 这就足够了
That's what it meant. That was enough.
就这样吗？
So that's it?
那么多的时间和金钱
All of that time and money
到头来 就换了个庸俗肤浅的象征？
spent on, what, just a cheap metaphor?
-这个象征挺深刻的 -闭嘴
-It's a pretty rich metaphor. -Oh, shut up!
我们得快点出去
We got to go. We got to go now.
-快 快走 -不 你们得留下
-Come on. Let's go. -No, no, no. You are staying here.
既然你们觉得这一切既美好又有诗意
You think it's all so sweet and poetic.
那就留下来 在临终前
Well, then you can stay here and spend your last moments
好好品味这个象征的深刻含义
pondering the richness of that metaphor.
-进去 -什么？不是吧
-Get in. -What? Come on, man.
-天啊 快进去 到棺材里去 -行
-Oh, God. Just get in. Get in the tomb. -Okay, okay.
活埋总比死埋好
It's better to be buried alive than buried dead, I guess.
-不是这样的 -真可惜
-It's really not. -You know, it is a shame, really.
这故事还是很精彩的
This is a hell of a story.
可惜你没命去讲了 我们走
Pity you won't be around to tell it. Come on.
可他们会死的
But they'll die.
你再扮圣母也得死
So will you if you don't stop being such a snowflake!
快过来
Get over here!
没关系
This is fine.
这并不是我从14岁起就一直做的噩梦
This is not an active nightmare I've had since I was 14 years old.
你跑那么快做什么？又不是比赛
Why are you going so fast? It's not a race.
等等 不！你做什么？快回来！
Wait, no! What are you doing? Come back here!
或许你是买下了这座岛
You may have bought the island,
但现在你的生死由这座岛决定
but now the island owns you!
你不能就这样抛下我
You can't just leave me here!
拉菲 你给我回来
Rafi! Come back!
我需要船
I need a boat!
停下
Hey, hey, stop! Stop!
救命啊
Help! Help!
一个当地人刚把我的船偷走了
One of the locals just stole my boat!
你有没有看到一个女人？
Have you seen a woman?
棕色头发 穿着一身亮片连身衣
She's a brunette in a sequined jumpsuit.
没有 她遇到什么麻烦了吗？
No. Is she in some sort of trouble?
说起来真好笑
It's kind of funny.
我以前曾经觉得…
I used to think this…
这种事很浪漫
this sort of thing was so romantic.
是吗？
Yeah?
被关在棺材里 即将被岩浆吞没
Being locked in a coffin about to be buried by lava,
还是…和死人同床共枕？
or… cuddling dead people?
和失去的爱共眠
Just laying down with a lost love.
就像塔哈一样
Like Taha did.
天啊
God.
我的天啊
Oh, God.
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起 我没能救你
I'm sorry that I couldn't save you.
对不起 我当不了达什
I'm sorry I couldn't be Dash.
你说得对
You're right.
你和达什完全不同
You're nothing like Dash.
你没有骑着白马来英雄救美
You didn't ride in on a white horse to save me.
你骑了辆借来的小摩托
You rode in on a… borrowed scooter
上面的消音器还是坏的
with a broken muffler.
是啊
Yeah.
我永远也写不出像你一样的达什
I never could've written a Dash like you.
因为我从来没见过
'Cause I never knew
像艾伦一样的达什
a Dash like Alan.
我因为太怕在生活中再次受到伤害
I was so afraid of being hurt by life again
所以就停止了生活
that I just stopped living.
看不到眼前美好的事物
Couldn't see the good things in front of me.
非常抱歉 我没有早点看到你
I'm just so sorry I didn't see you sooner.
我也有句心里话要说
I have a confession too.
我很喜欢我们这个新故事的发展方向
See, I was really liking where this new story of ours was headed.
我只想知道结局
I just wanted to see how it was gonna turn out, I guess.
《洛蕾塔和艾伦的大冒险》
The Adventures of Loretta and Alan.
不 得想个好点的书名
No, it would need a better title than that.
对 确实是
Yeah, definitely. Definitely.
对不起 只是…塔哈的大腿骨戳到我了
Sorry. Just… Taha's femur is poking me.
肯定是拉菲落下的
Rafi must have left that.
撬棍也能忘？我们能用来逃生的
How do you forget your crowbar? It's gonna help us escape.
不 他是故意留下的
No, he left it on purpose.
真好 我一直挺喜欢他的
Cool. I always liked him.
-一… -好
-One… -Okay.
-…二 三！ -好
-…two, three! -Okay.
他要是没先把我们困在这儿
I would've preferred him to not leave us here
那就更好了 不过…
in the first place, but…
可以了
Okay.
杜尔丘塞艾斯佩利斯
Dulcius ex asperis.
苦后更甜
Sweeter after difficulty.
向上 朝树跑
Go up! Run for the trees!
等等 不 算了 树着火了
Wait. Nope. Never mind. Trees are on fire.
好
Okay.
我们可以再从隧道爬出去
We can go back through the tunnel.
不 隧道没戏了
Nope. Tunnel's a no-go.
好 还有什么想法就快说吧
Okay. I'm open to other ideas.
水在流动 我们可以顺水游进海里
There's a current. We can follow it into the ocean.
我们怎么知道另一边有什么？
How do we know what's on the other side?
我们不知道
We don't.
想知道只有一个办法
There's only one way to find out.
-起湿疹也值了 -是吗？
-Worth the rash. -Yeah?
艾伦？
Alan?
艾伦
Alan!
Alan?
艾伦
Alan!
谢天谢地 你还活着
Oh, my God! You're alive!
-我还活着 -天啊 我还以为我把你害死了
-I'm alive. -Oh, my God. I thought I killed you.
那是贝丝吗？
Is that Beth?
洛蕾塔
Loretta!
贝丝
Beth!
-贝丝 -贝丝
-Beth! -Beth!
贝丝
Beth!
贝丝 你来了
Beth, you're here!
你怎么来了？
Why are you here?
我说过 有我在别怕 姑娘
I told you I got your back, girl!
真对不起
I'm so sorry!
我把连身衣弄坏了
I destroyed the jumpsuit!
什么？
What?
没事 以后再说
Never mind! Later.
我在山洞里找到一个英国人
I found a British guy in a cave.
我原本以为是个小男孩 但他长了一脸大胡子
I thought he was a little boy, but he has a full beard.
贝丝 他就是费尔法克斯 就是他绑架了我们
Beth, that's Fairfax! He kidnapped us!
他是个坏人 贝丝 他杀了我的教官
He's a bad guy, Beth! He killed my trainer!
抓住他
Get him!
把他拿下
Stop him!
有我在别怕 姑娘
I got your back, girl.
你跑什么？这是艘船
Where were you running? It's a boat.
这人真搞笑
This guy's hilarious.
我帮你
Got you.
游到石头上去
Swim over to the rock!
-我帮你 不 是我来帮你 -我帮你
-I don't got you. No, I got you. -I got you.
我们来了 没事了
We're gonna get you. It's gonna be okay.
“他在附近的一块岩石上栖身
"Finding refuge on a nearby rock,
将她从水里救了上来
he lifted her from the water,
他强壮的手臂将她的身体拉近
his powerful arms pulling her body close.
艾伦低语…”
Alan whispered…"
嘘 你现在安全了
Shh. You're safe now.
“在那一刻 洛蕾塔感觉到
"In that moment, Loretta could feel
一场新的冒险即将开始”
a new adventure was just beginning."
《火焰皇冠》
“死里逃生后 让人心跳加快的激情
"The heart-pounding passion of the narrow escape
激起了洛蕾塔对他的渴望
only inflamed Loretta's desire for him.
她期待着他的炙热岩浆
She was thirsty for the hot lava
随着一阵阵脉动 从他的…”
soon to be pulsing from his…"
精彩部分到了 可不许停
Don't you go stopping right at the good part.
她早就见怪不怪了
It's nothing she hasn't read before.
我没骗你吧？
Didn't I tell you?
世上最美的海滩
The most beautiful beach in the world.
一会儿有空 我带你去魔幻海湾转转？
Maybe later, I'll show you the Cove of Enchantment?
不了 你带兰迪去吧
No, you can take Randy.
记住 你是我的柏拉图式男性朋友
Remember, you are my platonic man friend.
柏拉图？这个词怪好听的
Platonic? I like the sound of that.
不懂是什么意思 但很好听
Not sure what it means, but I like the sound of it.
给你 兰迪
Here you go, Randy.
-亲爱的 -你真是个天使 谢谢你
-My dear. -You are an angel. Thank you.
你怎么知道的？
How did you know?
这样结束签书会很不错吧？
Nice way to end a book tour, right?
其实 我有一句名言
You know, I have a phrase
想在这个时候说
I like to use in moments like these, actually.
接下来呢？
Quid deinde?
是拉丁语 意思是“接下来呢？”
It's Latin. It means, "What's next?"
你怎么想？
Quid cogitas?
布卡迪派波餐馆
Buca di Beppo.
-我只会一句拉丁语 -不 是啊
-Yeah. I know zero other Latin. -No. Yes.
我特意查了一句 就为了现在用的
I looked it up for this moment right now.
所以 接下来到底要做什么呢？
So, what does come next?
-你会怎么写？ -我不知道
-How would you write this? -I don't know.
-你会怎么写？ -真的要让我来写？
-How would you write it? -Do we really want me to write this?
-试试看嘛 -好吧 我来写
-Just try. Take a stab at it. -Okay. I'll write it.
好
Okay.
“我们…他们…站在沙滩上”
"We were-- They were… standing on a beach."
交代地点 让读者知道我们在哪里
Sets the stage for the audience. They know where we are.
你已经在笑了 你为什么笑我？
You're already laughing. Why are you laughing at me?
-我没有笑你 这是微笑 -你有
-I'm not laughing. I'm smiling. -You are.
“棕榈树下面站着一个
"There are palm trees above a brown
树皮棕色头发的少女
bark-like hair of the maiden.
有一只死水母…”
There is a dead jellyfish--"
你只是在描述你实际看到的东西
All you're doing is describing what you're actually seeing right now.
“他很紧张 因为他真的喜欢她”
"He's nervous because he really likes her."
写得很好
It's nice writing.
-谢谢 -不客气
-Thanks. -You're welcome.
我继续
I'll keep going.
“他深深地看着她的眼睛
"He looked deep in her eyes.
唯一能与那海洋中的脉动相媲美的
The only thing that could compare to the pulse of that ocean
就是那一阵阵搏动…”
was the throbbing in the--"
-不 你不能搏动 -为什么不能？
-Okay, no, you can't throb. -Why not?
不能一上来就搏动
Can't come out of the gate with a throb.
-你就总搏 -我不会一开始就搏
-You throb all the time. -I don't come out of the gate with it.
-你得争取到 -你怎么就成了搏动的行家了？
-You have to earn the throb. -Who made you the queen of throb?
一般要等到第四章
It's usually a chapter four thing.
要在第四章时恰当地出现
You want it brought up appropriately in four.
我觉得你每章都有搏动 “有节奏的律动”
I think you throb in all the chapters. "Pulsating."
那是搏动的前奏
It's a precursor to throb.
-“忽快忽慢” -直接跳到第五章了
-"Undulating." -You just jumped to five.
-那就只是接吻行吗？ -一个普通的吻？
-How 'bout they just kiss? Why not? -Just like a regular kiss?
对 就像章节刚开始时的那种吻
Yeah. Like a beginning-of-the-chapter kiss.
我很会写开始…
I'm good at starting--
怎么样？有什么评语吗？
How was that? Any notes?
就第一章而言还是很不错的
Very good first chapter attempt.
我的娘…
Mother--
你死了
You were dead.
脑浆直接迸到我喉咙里
Your brains came out of your face and hit the back of my throat.
-他在我嘴里 -别说他在你嘴里
-He was in my mouth. -Don't say he was in your mouth.
-我能尝到你的味道 -真别这么说
-I could taste you. -Don't ever say that.
我们只利用了百分之十的大脑
We only use 10% of our brain,
所以我就换到另外的百分之十了
so I just switched to another 10%.
那你没事？
So, you're okay?
百分百的
One hundred percent.
也就是百分之十
Meaning 10%.
我们还以为你死了
We thought you were dead.
当然 我有些愤怒的情绪需要化解
Naturally, I have some anger issues I need to let go of.
-当然 -还有怨恨
-Of course. -And resentment.
见到你真好 哥们
So good to see you, man.
好 不要再聊天了
Okay, let's keep the chatter down.
闭上双眼 重新将意念集中在呼吸上
We're closing our eyes and reconnecting to our breath.
很好
Great.
字幕翻译：纪小敏